<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
                <title>Zach Tratar</title>
                <description>Ramblings on startups, design, engineering, and political philosophy.</description>
                <link>http://zachtratar.com</link>
                <atom:link href="http://zachtratar.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Maxims &amp;amp; Inspiration</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though Spock fans would disagree, we’re all guided by our emotions. When they arise through passion, we can channel them to produce and create wonderous things. When our emotions dull or lower, we have a natural inclination to dwell and despair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I began thinking about this, I grew curious. Could a routine help reinforce productive emotions and truly mitigate – not just ignore – the reverse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that emotions have two primary sources: preceding emotions and logical deductions. If we believe ourselves to be in a position of greatness, it is easy to get excited and attempt to manifest such a position. If one tells us we are incapable of something or that our ideas have no merit, we question our own capability and reinforce that belief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External happenstances that guide our emotions are unavoidable. Some may consider that to be a bit scary, but we all have a powerful tool to fight the good fight: internal dialogue! With our own thought, we all occasionally have epiphanies – small and large – that makes us &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; good. And we should feel good; we just figured something out! Go team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where do these epiphanies come from and once we have them and how often do they really stick with us? I found that I rarely kept track of mine and, as a result, kept asking myself the same questions over and over again. These epiphanies are logical in nature and wildly differ from person to person, but they certainly affect emotions. Since logic can be re-stated time and time again, perhaps we can use it to our advantage and guide ourselves towards a consistently healthy state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-called-a-maxim&quot;&gt;It’s called a Maxim!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard either the terms “Maxim” or “Proverb” before. They mean the same thing: a short statement of truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Life is really simple, but we insist on making it complicated.” - Confucious&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Very little is is needed to make a happy life; it is all within yourself, in your way of thinking.” - Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You have power over your mind — not outside events. Realize this, and you will find strength.” - Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcus Aurelius, Emperor of Rome, is considered to be one of the wisest men to have ever lived, but even he realized his own weaknesses. So what did he do? He set up a daily routine to battle them. Upon waking, Marcus would recite his own personalized maxims and ponder their meaning; these were quick refreshers that helped guide the rest of his day, week, month, and year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern-society-and-me&quot;&gt;Modern Society and Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that modern society prioritizes sources of inspiration in a completely backwards manner: ease-of-discovery dominates efficacy. People hang inspirational posters, collect items on Pinterest, and even go searching for the oh-so-loved “like” on social networks. We look for small glimmers of social proof and meaning through luck — we think “perhaps the outside world holds the same things to be true as my inner self!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much time does that leave for us to focus and reflect upon our own thoughts? Not enough, in my opinion, and oh what a shame! We understand ourselves better than anyone else, which means we &lt;em&gt;resonate with our own, personal discoveries the most!&lt;/em&gt; What would it mean to you if you had an essentially unlimited, effective source of inspiration? We can create sources of daily inspiration that are targeted towards our most foundational of needs, optimized for our current state of life, and — most importantly — &lt;em&gt;guide us specifically towards who we want to be&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although cute, no kitten on a tree that says “hang in there” is going to prove comparable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a little experiment and pushed myself to create a couple maxims every week. As I set aside 15 minutes every morning to go over my own list and think in peace, I found the benefits to be immediete and immense. Just like starting the day with a win by making my bed, I’ve found that I feel more able and positive when I calibrate my thoughts. It makes small problems stay small — or at least &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; small — and become more manageable. Oh, and it makes even the smallest of wins fit into a larger framework, which means their value isn’t simply forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it helped me, I thought I’d share with everyone who might be interested and end up reading this. Here are a couple things I’ve learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It takes repetition. If not every day, every other day seems to be nearly as effective (but there’s definitely a difference).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll eventually have a large list of maxims if you keep at it. As you keep creating, also focus on condensing any overlapping points. It needs to remains clear and concise… which brings me to the next point.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating your own maxims helps you understand a little bit more about yourself. Answering “Who am I?” becomes quite a bit easier, and the result more vivid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Targeting your current emotional state when reflecting is really effective. Just lose a battle? Focus on the war.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a proponent of Science, I also want to note that none of this was scientific in the slightest. Shoot me a tweet if you’re thinking about trying this out; I’d love to hear about your discoveries!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//maxims-and-inspiration.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//maxims-and-inspiration.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Followr V1: New Features and Insights</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachtratar.com/followr.html&quot;&gt;wrote about&lt;/a&gt; and launched Followr two weeks ago, a chrome extension designed to help people gain traction on twitter through automated means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was truly surprised by people’s reactions. I expected to be crushed by the community, but nearly everyone was kind and positive.  Oh – there was one person who called me mentally delusional. &lt;em&gt;Thanks, stranger!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received so much great feedback that I decided to act quickly. Today, I’m releasing Followr v1.0.0, the 2nd public release. You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://ztratar.github.io/followr&quot;&gt;download it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features-in-v1&quot;&gt;New Features In V1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History &amp;amp; Conversion Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now see what actions Followr is taking in the “History” page. When favorites convert into followers, the specific tweet is marked as “Converted!” You can also see your total gained followers from Followr on the “Setup” page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granular Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most requested features was a blacklist, and so it came to be. Followr will never favorite tweets that contain words in the blacklist. Multi-word search queries were also returning poorly relevant results, so Followr now searches for exact query strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Interface &amp;amp; Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous interface was missing a lot of highly relevant information. The new tutorial guides and informs new users. The extension popout now shows you which account Followr is using. I rebuilt the entire interface front the ground up, so pictures will do more justice than words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/followrV1/setup-tab.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/followrV1/history-tab.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/followrV1/progress.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stealth / Anti-Detection Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening up Followr would previously append a ?followr=true variable to the window — lame. Followr now uses script injection to control Twitter’s native frontend controls. The time interval that dictates when Followr runs has also been randomized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-whats-next&quot;&gt;So, what’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still much work to be done and Followr is open-source, so let me know if you want to help out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Query Effectiveness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m satisfied with the interface and basic favoriting mechanisms, I want to make fewer actions convert into more followers. To do this, the search queries will be optimized using previous data. I would probably be able to do a better job on this if I centralized some data, but I’m not sure that’s a good choice. Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Cleanup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admittedly fell into callback hell. The code could use a good ol’ refactoring to become squeaky clean. I’m thinking about implementing the next version using Promises, which would be quite fun. The CSS is also getting quite gross — I’ll switch over to LESS &amp;amp; Grunt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-lovely-reviews&quot;&gt;Some lovely reviews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/followrV1/reviews.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//followrv1.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//followrv1.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Popcorn Time And Tech's Duty To Do The Right Thing</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When I first started writing this post, I didn’t know where it would end up. This post covers many topics — maybe too many — so I want to emphasize one thing right now: the last section means the most to me. If you’re only going to read for 15-20 seconds, please skip to the last section. Thanks, Zach.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-apathy&quot;&gt;My Apathy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the first time I used Napster. I was 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cousin and I were playing video games when his older sister began to play a new Blink-182 song on her computer. I ran over to check it out and saw a blue download bar moving at speeds I had never seen - turns out my Uncle had just bought a T1 internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cousin and I stayed up all night downloading music illegally. We didn’t know any better. We had only a faint idea of copyright law and this program, so readily accessible, surely didn’t &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; bad. Bad things are hard to do, &lt;em&gt;right?&lt;/em&gt; Plus, this was fun! Bad things can’t be fun, &lt;em&gt;right?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I stopped downloading and torrenting files years ago, I was never truly disturbed by pirating. I didn’t like the idea of taking someones work for free, but my disdain wasn’t at a level where I felt like I wanted to say anything, let alone take action. When I watched Governments destroy the lives of The Pirate Bay creators, I vilified the Governments. If my friend loaded up a torrent to stream on a projector, I wouldn’t think twice… I’d just go in the kitchen and make some popcorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;popcorn-time&quot;&gt;Popcorn Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was shown Popcorn Time a couple weeks ago and my mind was subsequently blown. Popcorn Time was beautiful — it was the first beautiful pirating application I had ever seen. I could search for nearly any movie and have it playing in a matter of seconds with two clicks. This was something my Mom could use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time, in that brief moment of realization, I felt scared — even sorry — for the media industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they say, with great power comes great responsibility. Popcorn Time is too good at what it does. I know where to draw the line for my own uses of technology, but most ten year olds, for example, aren’t going to give a shit. Nothing easy and fun can be that bad, &lt;em&gt;right?&lt;/em&gt; They’re going to download and download until one day, their parents finally ask “Hey, what is that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, you know, “it’s just this app where I can get any movie for free!” Many parents won’t know any better. The kids will install it for them, skip the fear-provoking warning screen, and move the entire, blissfully ignorant family into torrenting territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This territory has been historically small due to the illicit nature of piracy and its accompanying environment. Back in the early 2000s, Napster, Limewire, and Kazaa were distribution machines for not only music, but also computer viruses. If people didn’t weren’t technically savvy, they were likely to download something stupid and brick their computer. Many people chose to not run the risk. The suspect conditions surrounding piracy still live today; most torrenting sites are plastered with porn ads and get-rich-quick schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with all of these things preventing piracy, over half of all Americans have admitted to partaking. Half — that’s a lot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.dailytech.com/nimage/Piracy_Percentages_Wide.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove the unpleasing experience from piracy and what can happen? Popcorn Time will not be the last application open this door. It has proven that you can layer a great, seemingly clean experience on top of an illicit foundation. They’ve shown that doing so can result in a flock of people wanting more — after all, everyone needs to save money in these tough times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how many people would use something like Popcorn Time, but I think the number could be extraordinarily high — so high that it may not only do significant damage, but also shake the media industry into a partial collapse. I don’t want that to happen. The media industry creates beautiful pieces of artwork that help inspire and define generations. It enables dreams and floods people with shared imaginations in a sometimes otherwise dark world. It’s an important asset for this nation and the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-media-industry&quot;&gt;The Media Industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The media industry knows they need to adapt to continue making money, but how should they adapt? It’s a difficult question to answer, so let’s get some perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire music industry, for example, is not massive — overall revenue last year was only $16.5 billion. WhatsApp, a single company, sold for $19 billion to Facebook last month. The kingpins of media are attempting to protect their revenue streams to the best of their abilities and they see piracy as their primary enemy. With limited capital, the best means of exerting power is through… you guessed it, Government!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for them (and us), they don’t collectively understand technology. Every attempt they make to fix copyright protection results in proposed legislation that tramples internet freedom. I think there are many people in tech who would be on their side if real compromise was put on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As ineffective as the media industry may be at proposing such compromise, I’m also seeing apathy from tech industry leadership. We constantly put the ball in the media industry’s court to create legislation before we say “No! That sucks too!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So again, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; should they adapt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be controversial, but I don’t think they possess the abilities to cleanly save themselves. If they’re on their own, I believe there will be collateral damage. Internet freedom will continually be in the crosshairs, albeit unnecessary, if the media industry doesn’t get help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the goals for the media industry are pretty clear, so why doesn’t the tech industry give it a shot?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legislation that hits a good middle ground is possible if and only if the right people are working on it. I think the leaders of the tech industry need to to go the extra mile, work with Hollywood, and spearhead their own version of fresh, internet-preserving copyright protection law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doing-the-right-thing&quot;&gt;Doing The Right Thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just ranted about the media industry — can these same concepts be generalized? Should they be? Let’s think philosophically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology possesses great power — the likes of which are being scrutinized by the world. Who are these techies on buses? Why can’t I afford rent anymore? Why are robots replacing hard-working people in factories?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As technology moves forward, it is inevitable that it will grow in both good and bad ways. “Software is eating the world” — think about that sentence for the second. To engineers it is a rallying cry for beautiful efficiency, to others it sounds flat out horrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all human. Transition is extremely hard — it is emotionally draining upon individuals and society. For technology to make the most optimal impact, it must be smooth and welcomed, its benefits clear as day and its intentions unquestionably pure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People should be uniting around Science and Technology, not against it. Technology must be viewed as something magical instead of malicious. It is so easy for technology, computing especially, to seem cold, self-interested, and reckless; making it friendly, warm, and benevolent will take effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology has enabled piracy to flip the media industry upside down and that is just the beginning. Very soon, technology will start having more pronounced effects on labor and manufacturing through 3D printing and the internet of things. We won’t be talking about piracy and media then, we’ll be talking about millions of jobs and economic conditions never studied in recorded history. As a whole, our quest for innovation must be balanced with careful wisdom and — I’ll say it — an appreciation for the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot enact change that affects billions of lives and then say “fend for yourself, figure out the new rules”. I believe we must hold out our hands, share   a vision for what is newly possible, and, most importantly, show people what role they can play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is in our ability — &lt;em&gt;no ones else’s&lt;/em&gt;, and thus I believe it is our duty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to my friends for feedback on this post: Andrew Chapello, Andrew Hsu, Peter Pelberg, and Mustafa Khan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//popcorn.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//popcorn.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Followr, Twitter Bots, and Ethical Considerations</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter has a massive problem: new users have an extremely difficult time getting started. People who give it a chance and invest real time into the network usually fizzle out after a couple days, leaving without a clue as to what makes it great. Case in point: I now consider myself an active Twitter user, though it took 6 tries and 5 years to finally ‘get it’. Oh, and I’m in the frigin’ tech industry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you join Twitter you have no followers — it’s like being brought into an empty room and being told “have fun!” Even though you can stare at a wall for 2 minutes before leaving, the average person is going to leave a heck of a lot quicker. You can import your friends and contacts lists, but that’s a long shot – chances are those people aren’t using Twitter either. For people to follow you, you need to fill out a fancy bio, tweet some interesting things, and hope people find you by luck. Oh, but Twitter’s sign up process must help… right? Wrong. It tells you to follow influencers, the people who are least likely to listen to what you have to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these barriers hit you in the face before you derive any value from the product. I believe Twitter has a potential thousands of times greater than its current footprint, but it has to fix this problem. Until it does, I believe helping them out a bit to be a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunity-in-the-depths&quot;&gt;Opportunity In The Depths&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of Twitter is its simple architecture. There is a lot you can do with it; even though the default functionality is lacking, we can make it better ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we make Twitter better? I think there can be many pieces to this puzzle and now is the time to get creative. One of the best solutions I’ve found lies in the most controversial of places: automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every “traditional” twitter bot I’ve seen was written with two goals in mind: First, to avoid detection and second, to gain followers in vast numbers. Absolutely everything else is at the expense of these two goals, and thus, bots tarnish the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That got me thinking, could you make a bot that truly enhances the network?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked around, many people seemed to have a vendetta against all automation within social networks. I think this is due to historically poor bot design. Automation itself is not bad, but is in fact critical to the effectiveness of all modern applications. Certain tasks simply suit themselves towards automation: email newsletters, notification clustering, information collection and analysis, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter bots can take many types of actions, including following and then unfollowing users, auto-replying, and favoriting tweets. All of these actions are disingenuous, favoriting being the least. That’s the negative. The positive lies with the cold, hard fact that favoriting tweets gets you followers — the same possible followers you likely need as a new user to make Twitter useful. So what if you could outweigh the negative with the positive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introducing-followr&quot;&gt;Introducing Followr&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m releasing a little project called &lt;a href=&quot;http://ztratar.github.io/followr&quot;&gt;Followr&lt;/a&gt; to the public. Followr is a Twitter bot, pure and simple, but it aims to be very different than the status quo in three ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instead of being a menace to the Twitter ecosystem, &lt;strong&gt;Followr’s goal is to be the first truly tasteful bot&lt;/strong&gt; — the first bot designed to actually help holistically improve Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Followr is open-source&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ll be happy if others pitch in to make it even better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Followr is a chrome extension. It uses the native Twitter website as a proxy to work its magic, so &lt;strong&gt;it can’t be shut down with ease&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between Followr and traditional Twitter bots lies in the net value created. A tasteful bot does vastly more good than harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be lying if I said Followr is a ‘pure’ tool. The truth is that results matter more: Followr makes Twitter a more friendly, usable network. It enables more people to discover you through shared interests. It can theoretically help give a voice to every individual whose at an unfair advantage because they came to the game late. I sincerely hope it can help you as it has helped the others I started it for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-it-work-how-will-it-work&quot;&gt;How does it work, how will it work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version, released today, has minimal functionality. It takes a list of topics you like, searches for tweets about them, and favorites a couple of them. Whereas traditional bots favorite a massive amount of tweets and spam, Followr only favorites 12 or so tweets every 30 minutes your browser is open. For Twitter members with high follower counts this won’t do much, but for those new to the system it can make the experience. Followr also rewards you with more favorites when you interact with others through legitimate discussions and retweets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though much improvement is still possible, after observing the habits of users, I’ve found that Followr, in its current form, creates a net positive value. I think it could made substantially more effective by implementing and improving in some key areas, such as the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intelligent Tweet Selection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some automatically favorited tweets will resonate with you while others won’t. A better bot can increase the number of the former and minimize the latter, making the favorites more valuable and giving you better connections with better people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Behavior Driven Rewards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning on Followr and never going back to Twitter would be a terrible thing. This is why Followr should learn your behavior over time and reward you for doing good. If you use Twitter like a bot, Followr should ideally shut itself off. There are many ideas that can be explored in this vertical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many people followed me organically vs Followr? Right now, the analytics for that answer aren’t built. Followr can’t do some basic things, like give weighted priority to one topic over another or check if you’re already followed by a user it’s favoriting. It also has a severe “pretty graph” deficiency, which most certainly requires a remedy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whatever you can think up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have an idea? We can talk about it on Github Issues or on Twitter! Shoot me a tweet &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/zachtratar&quot;&gt;@zachtratar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some will disagree with this approach and that’s ok. I know it’s a tad controversial, but I find it naive to deem good automation impossible. It can be done. Since Followr is a chrome extension, it will auto-update on people’s browsers as improvements are created. I’m excited to what the future holds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ztratar.github.io/followr&quot;&gt;You can download Followr here&lt;/a&gt;. If you like it, please review it! Don’t like it? I’m all ears.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//followr.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//followr.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>My Reply To Senator Feinstein</title>
                                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dianne Feinstein, Senator for California and Head of the Intelligence committee, just sent out an email supporting the NSA surveillance programs. I put her email in the comments section and the PDF she attached can be found &lt;a href=&quot;/files/Feinstein-Chronicle.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to read the full text. This is my reply.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senator Feinstein,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all due respect, the beginning line in your second paragraph has already been proven untrue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“First, please be assured that the NSA does not conduct mass surveillance on U.S. citizens.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is well known now that the NSA conducts varies degrees of dragnet data collection. If you are limiting the definition of surveillance to only information that is being looked at &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; by human eyes, then you would be correct. I believe that dragnet data collection is surveillance. My actions, my words, my emotions – everything – is collected. It may not be scrutinized now, but it can be scrutinized later. Any such program removes ones freedom to act – people act different when watched. Usually for the better, I’ll admit, but that is certainly not for the Government to decide. The Sedition acts of the 1800s are a prime example, and I believe this to be of equivalent importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Americans need liberty. The world needs liberty. It is a constitutional requirement that my liberty be protected, and unfortunately, I see it slipping away week by week as select people claim there is no surveillance. How far will you go to fight for my liberty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only ask one thing: please ensure you understand the issue from this perspective – the perspective where definitions are a bit more cloudy than Merriam-Webster. The perspective where pure data collection is a form of surveillance and must be stopped in all forms of dragnet operation. When you vote or propose legislation moving in that direction, you re-affirm a vote from me and thousands of others. When you vote for dragnet data collection, you are voting to limit liberty in all its forms – the antithesis of American pride and power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Precedent is important and I understand the kind of position you’re in is not only complicated, but career-threatening. As the head of the Intelligence community, it may seem that many advocates promoting the same things as me aren’t listening to your side. That might be true, but I sincerely hope that doesn’t lead towards an overall generalization clouding the righteous passions of many citizens. That would be a travesty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want my children to live in a United States of America that promotes peace and, instead of pushing forward the status quo of “us vs them” and “terrorists are inherently evil at birth”, does its best to resolve these issues through intelligent foreign policy and humanitarian aid. I want to live in an America that is a shining city on top of a hill – one that strives to take the high road at every possible moment. Terrorism is a tricky issue – the issue of the century – but it cannot be solved by brute force means. Terrorism is deep-seated anger, hate, and revenge. It is irrational, yet that doesn’t mean it has to be fought with irrational or impure means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founding fathers said that freedom is achievable when liberty is balanced with order. I believe strongly in order, but we also must try different approaches to achieve it and hold each program underneath a spotlight that ranks effectiveness and efficiency. The net loses for Americans through the NSA programs severely outweigh the benefits we derive if, and only if we can maintain order and security through other means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are these other means? I’d like different answers explored through our great legislative and governmental processes. Please make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a good day,
Zach&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//feinstein.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//feinstein.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>What I'm Grateful For</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of my friends recently shared a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oHv6vTKD6lg&amp;amp;feature=c4-overview-vl&amp;amp;list=PLzvRx_johoA8PC6S5k5S2SszRQOR8oSEa&quot;&gt;great video about gratitude&lt;/a&gt; and how it correlates with one’s own happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was driving home last night when I started thinking about this video again. I thought: what am I grateful for? Quite ironically, right when this thought popped in my mind some jagoff cut me off and nearly hit a Prius to my right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not very grateful for that guy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in all seriousness, time to list off some great stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful for genuine people.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s too damned easy to get caught up in fake facades and societal expectations these days. People who challenge this social status quo and simply represent their true selves are the most beautiful of all.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to be in a world and nation rich in infrastructure.&lt;/strong&gt; The modern world is amazing. For those lucky enough to be born with access to the internet, modern transportation, complex resource distribution systems, etc, the world is quite literally our playground. We can learn whatever we want, do whatever we want, say whatever we want – build whatever we want. Modern infrastructure has given us the means to attain a level of individual liberty unattainable by our ancestors. Sure, it also comes with societal expectations and imperfect systems, but I think those are merely bumps on a long road; they can be overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful for the people, both modern and ancient, who built the infrastructure of the world.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes everyone – not just the CEOs of the olden days. I didn’t invent the car, but I get to drive one. I didn’t discover electricity, but I get to show you this set of words because millions of electrons move in unison. I didn’t have to fight for civil rights, but I get to have friends of multiple cultures and races. Every single thing we know and use on this planet was discovered or created by someone just like us. Each invention and piece of forward progress started as as small idea in someone’s mind and grew into something grand. Even though so many problems still exist, so many have been solved. Mad props, old timers!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful for everyone fighting to make tomorrow better than today.&lt;/strong&gt; The world presents us many opportunities and it’s not easy to determine how impactful our role truly is. Being self-critical in this environment and taking action to ensure your in the right place requires bravery, pure and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And onto some of the personal stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to have such a loving family.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s always wonderful to talk to my mom, cousins, aunts and uncles. They’re great people and whenever I chat with any of them I feel like I’m home.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to have the best friends in the world.&lt;/strong&gt; You all are frigin’ rockstars and have helped me in so many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to live in one of the most beautiful locations I’ve ever known.&lt;/strong&gt; The sunrise peering over the mountains in the bay makes all morning commutes irrationally energizing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to have an awesome set of colleagues.&lt;/strong&gt; Having managed so many parts of a large recruiting process, I’m reminded all the time how unique and rare it is to have this group around me and fighting for the same mission.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to be working on something that is truly meaningful.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s all about bringing people together in ways they didn’t believe were possible… helping people find their true home. Home sweet home!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are you grateful for? I’d like to know if you’re willing to
share. Tweet it at me below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//grateful.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//grateful.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>PRISM: A Final Blow To Functioning Democracy?</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;In the unlikely chance you found yourself here and have no idea who Ed Snowden is, you need to watch this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/video/2013/jun/09/nsa-whistleblower-edward-snowden-interview-video&quot;&gt;12-minute interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t have time? Seriously try and make time. If you care at all about your privacy or the principles upon which America was founded, watch it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prism&quot;&gt;PRISM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single primary document Ed Snowden leaked outlines an NSA program called “PRISM”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through all of the speculation, it seems the most likely scenario is that PRISM is a data-collection utility. It connects the NSA internal database to specialized, intermediary servers within companies that provide communication services. This includes Google, Facebook, Verizon, Yahoo, AT&amp;amp;T, Apple, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been hearing the Government say over and over that PRISM and these data tools do not “target” American citizens, but according to Edward Snowden the system “ingests everyone by default.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woah! Those are definitely contradictory statments. Who do we believe? This answer is determined by how we define “target”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s well known amongst the startup and data communities that you want to track almost everything since data storage is cheap. It’s a best practice. Dig a little deeper into news sources and it’s easy to determine that the NSA does, in fact, ingest everything about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “targeting” language being used by the White House most likely implies how they &lt;em&gt;analyze&lt;/em&gt; the data. But again, it’s never best practice to simply ignore recorded data. Instead, depending on what you’re tracking, you’ll just weight data patterns you’re looking for. Turns out that &lt;em&gt;no one&lt;/em&gt; is exempt from this analysis! The White House claims it does not target Americans simply because they &lt;em&gt;attempt&lt;/em&gt; to only look for foreigners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a catch: their attempts are failing! Their algorithm to determine whether or not a person is a foreigner only has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informationweek.com/security/privacy/nsa-prism-inside-the-modern-surveillance/240156341&quot;&gt;51% confidence interval&lt;/a&gt;. Just under half the people analyzed by their software are, in fact, American citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we know we’re being recorded and likely analyzed, let’s jump into the high level of what this all means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-fall-of-functioning-democracy&quot;&gt;The Fall of Functioning Democracy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;History tends to repeat itself as complex sociological and governmental patterns emerge. Even as far &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plato's_five_regimes&quot;&gt;back as Plato&lt;/a&gt;, there have been theorized cycles for governmental systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although history tends to show that true democracy performs the best, it – like everything – also has its weaknesses. There aren’t many huge points-of-failure in the system, but instead thousands of smaller vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no strong influence or unified government to cover these holes, spreading power can create a slowing of decision-making, inefficiencies in process, and thus both instability and mistrust. Instability leads to a populace that craves security, and as security increases over time, it almost always falls into tyranny. The founding fathers knew this, which led them to say things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Those who surrender freedom for security will not have, nor do they deserve, either one.” - Benjamin Franklin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This nation was founded upon the primary ideal of freedom. You as a citizen must never passively nor actively be hindered from thinking, acting, and speaking your mind. A functional democracy requires its populace to be both absolutely free and well-informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We the people – we who are entrusted to properly vote in the best legislators – are not informed in the slightest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US Government’s document classification system was originally created to protect documents that would, if released, harm national security. Unfortunately, it is frequently used to hide unpopular and apparently unconstitutional policies. If people do not have access to this critical information, then they, by definition, cannot be informed to the extent required to make intelligent voting decisions. Instead, the NSA has given themselves a “self-certification that they serve the national interest.” That doesn’t sound like democracy to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I ask you a question: what does it take to speak your mind? What if it’s controversial?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychologically, if someone is listening to you and can theoretically use information against you, you are less likely to speak. At that point, &lt;em&gt;you are no longer free&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even if you think you have nothing to hide, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kottke.org/13/06/you-commit-three-felonies-a-day&quot;&gt;think again&lt;/a&gt;. The justice system doesn’t always play nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I know you’re thinking “They’ll still never come after me”. But in that logic lies a tricky problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-we-should-all-care&quot;&gt;Why We Should All Care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cat is now out of the bag. The public now &lt;em&gt;knows&lt;/em&gt; that the US government is running PRISM-like surveillance programs. Before the leak, using data from programs like this to jail or suppress any individuals’ freedoms would entail high risk. The program could be exposed to the public and the intelligence agency would be under fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But using the data now is far less risky and will thus be used more often. If we allow governmental programs such as PRISM to exist, then we give the intelligence community the go-ahead to use this data in public forum, however that may evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t predict the future, but someone among the NSA will eventually think about building an API on top of it; someone will think about making the data decentralized; someone will think about making it universally accessible. We are on an extremely slippery slope. Edward Snowden spoke up because he believed that if he didn’t, our losses as a public would be “irrevocable”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irrevocable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This word truly means a lot because it is &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; used when describing software. Snowden himself stated that if he wanted to break down many of the NSA’s systems, he could. PRISM included, considering his unfettered access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is this irrevocable system? I think that the NSA is about to finish a new, highly advanced data collection/analysis system – one that makes PRISM and the other leaked systems look like children’s toys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With their non-democratic self-certification, the NSA is going to continue ingesting every piece of data is can get its hand on. All of your data in one place. It will be spread across numerous locations and have multiple backups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that information is put into the system, it will never cease-to-exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyber-warfare and complex system intrusions are becoming increasingly common. We cannot build perfect security systems – new flaws in seemingly-impervious systems are found all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When, &lt;em&gt;not if&lt;/em&gt;, there is a massive data leak, what will happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “they’ll still never come after me” mentality is now completely moot; we don’t even know who “they” are. Maybe it’s an identity thief; maybe it’s a foreign government – it could be &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our government is taking these actions in the name of security, but effectively all we’re doing is stockpiling ammo, 99.9% of which can only be shot back at ourselves. We then put that ammo behind a shoddy wall for safekeeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite obviously, this does not make us more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are we sure we want to live in that world? Are we sure our children and grand-children will want to live in that world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s completely possible that we are making that choice right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//prism.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//prism.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Training like Tesla: An Experiment of the Mind</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m going to undergo an experiment with which I am the test subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea manifested while I was reading “&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/My-Inventions-Autobiography-introduction-ebook/dp/B004W48LAG&quot;&gt;My Inventions: The autobiography of Nikola Tesla&lt;/a&gt;”. The man is believed among scientific minds to have been savant-like and it certainly shows in his writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easy to make assumptions as to how an engineer could write, but Nikola defies those assumptions. He defies the standards to which people apply him, and by all counts he did that in absolutely every field in his life. Almost no human to have ever lived has accomplished as much as Nikola.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any person who exhibits abilities seemingly beyond our grasp, we begin to wonder how they got there in the first place. What made them great? Did they eat their wheaties? Did they go through special training? Were they born with it? Entire debates have forged through history around nature versus nurture for the explicit purpose of understanding what makes one human being more productive to society than another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-power-of-imagination&quot;&gt;The power of imagination&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here, at least in the reference of Nikola, we have data. Well… we have what he wrote down, which we can only assume to be as honest as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What made Nikola great was his precise and grandiose imagination. He grew up with an intense visual imagination that tormented him when he was unable to control it. It would present itself forcibly unto his mind when he was trying to interact in the real world. He grew up without confidence in himself thinking that this was a shackle destined to cripple his life-long worth and validity. But he learned to control it. And for all the pain he suffered, the sheer beauty of the upside is hard to match. I could do no better to describe it than he:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I soon discovered that my best comfort was attained if I simply went on in my vision further and further, getting new impressions all the time, and so I began to travel; of course, in my mind. Every night, (and sometimes during the day), when alone, I would start on my journeys – see new places, cities and countries; live there, meet people and make friendship and acquaintances…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This I did constantly until I was about seventeen, when my thoughts turned seriously to invention. Then I observed to my delight that I could visualize with the greatest facility. I need no models, drawings or experiments. I could picture them all as real in my mind… I do not rush into actual work. When I get an idea, I start at once building it up in my imagination. I change the construction, make improvements and operate the device in my mind. It is absolutely immaterial to me whether I run my turbine in thought or test it in my shop.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;- Nikola Tesla&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an engineer or “builder” you’re probably feeling jealous right about now; or maybe you think he is crazy. Either way, this guy’s imagination was a private sandbox with zero limitations. It emulated reality so accurately that he could invent and discover in ways that others could not do in hundreds of lifetimes. The electricity powering your screen right now was surely, at least at point, transmitted as alternating current. Nikola did that. Let’s also not forget about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.org/tesla/ll/ll_whoradio.html&quot;&gt;Radio&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fi.edu/learn/case-files/tesla/motor.html&quot;&gt;Electric Motor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-this-an-innate-talent-or-is-it-developed&quot;&gt;Is this an innate talent or is it developed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday tasks are not usually intense enough to put stress on the imagination. They are relatively easy and entail things like planning out the next couple minutes of your day, writing short emails, or remembering where the checkbook is located.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But every so often we all face complicated problems. They start out simple enough and as higher-level goals, but at some point, as you mentally break them down, you hit a large wall. The clarity with which you can visualize, plan, and think is drastically reduced and you bring the process into the physical world through writing or drawing. UX Designers wireframe, engineers whiteboard or jump into code, interior designers start grabbing fabric samples, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t usually question this natural wall. But change your perspective on imagination for a moment and think of it &lt;em&gt;purely&lt;/em&gt; as a skill you can develop. Just as you can rate your other abilities – maybe you’re a great coder or orator – rate your imagination. How &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; is it to you right now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, it seems the utility provided by one’s imagination is in direct correlation with this wall’s location. The more in-depth you can think with absolute clarity before ramming into the barrier, the better use you will get out of your imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, we want to learn to move our wall; we want to push it further and further, inch by inch, until its limiting effects are diminished and we gain a newfound freedom in our own imagination. Nikola’s wall was miles and miles away during his peak but he admits to not having the same abilities as a child, so it seems that this is an ability one can foster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps Nikola’s mental travels, inventions, and constant use of his imagination trained him. Perhaps those experiences pushed his wall further and further until he was left with a giant sandbox. That’s the experiment I will attempt to undergo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-a-sandbox&quot;&gt;Building a sandbox&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, I am not attempting to say that I am more fit to do this than anyone else. In fact, my goal is to “prove” the opposite: I want to see if this ability is attainable by anyone. I want to experience the upside: a truly lean process of ideation and iteration that removes the physical complexities (one that would make &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Blank&quot;&gt;Steven Blank&lt;/a&gt; proud).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I find it easy to rate, with precision, my ability to imagine &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt;; I think I know where my wall is located. As such, I’m going to do my best to track any progress I make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll train the same way Nikola did: first imagining things I’ve already seen and places I’ve already been. My childhood home, neighborhood, travel destinations, products I use, objects, etc. I’m going to imagine the people I’ve met, the sounds I’ve heard, and even the emotions I’ve felt. Following that I’ll see if I can go further down the path of creating new experiences and inventions. Specifically, the idea is to create increasingly complex scenes and visualize increasingly complex problems until the wall is inches away. At that point, the test is whether or not the wall can be moved and if it will stay once moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nikola traversed the worlds of physics and electromagnetism in his mind. He manifested his findings into real world developments. I hope the same can be done for the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more data, the better the experiment: If anyone is interested in embarking on this journey/test with me, let me know (email, twitter, facebook – they all work). I’m beyond excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5631577/blog/Screen%20Shot%202013-04-12%20at%203.27.01%20PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;Marc thinks I will go insane&quot; /&gt;
	Thank you to those who helped review this post: Eric, Andrew, Vinay, Chris, Rajaishi, Raj, Dino, and Nik

	... and Marc
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//tesla.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//tesla.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>The New Facebook News Feed: A UX Breakdown</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet is blowing up with sensationalized articles on the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/about/newsfeed&quot;&gt;Facebook News Feed&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not a fan of that, so instead let’s talk about design principles and user behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-stories-are-frigin-huge&quot;&gt;The “Stories” are frigin HUGE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the biggest surprise in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple emotions you want to achieve in feeds. The first is zen – it’s calming to get lost and just keep scrolling. The second is usually balanced chaos. The more stuff you see, the more active the site feels. Facebook still has zen, but the chaos seems to have been thrown out in favor of further simplicity. It takes more scrolling to see less items, but nothing is fighting for your attention. Instead of thinking, you’re either looking at the top most “story” or you’re scrolling to the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile works the same way. As you move from phone to computer the experience won’t be nearly as jarring. If the feeds are identical on mobile and desktop, I wouldn’t be surprised if they release a feature later to sync your spot on the feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-facebooks-biggest-change-yet-but-the-risk-is-being-overestimated&quot;&gt;This is Facebook’s biggest change yet, but the risk is being overestimated&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/07/facebook-risks-it-all/&quot;&gt;Techcrunch’s article&lt;/a&gt; says this is their most risky change yet. After the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook_Beacon&quot;&gt;Beacon&lt;/a&gt; incident years ago, Facebook has become a more data-driven company. They have a huge data research team pillaging their logs to track user behavior. Is this is a big change? You betcha… it’s the home page! On web applications with a news feed system, a heavy majority of all interaction is done on the home page. Is this a risky choice? Not really. They’re releasing is slowly and watching the data. Risk is mitigated as they iterate – and they will. Compared to the risk presented when Facebook opened up their &lt;a href=&quot;http://money.cnn.com/2007/05/24/technology/facebook.fortune/&quot;&gt;first developer APIs&lt;/a&gt;, this is nothing (and it’s only because of the data).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sorting-has-been-optimized-out&quot;&gt;Sorting has been optimized out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the feed is being changed to a combination of “new” and “popular”. This is not done very often. Facebook can only do this effectively because their average user comes back to the site multiple times a day. This also means that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://edgerank.net/&quot;&gt;demonized edge-rank algorithm&lt;/a&gt; is probably taking more of a backseat or was altered substantially. Changing an algorithm from being entirely score based to purely chronologically dependent isn’t easy at scale. I can’t be 100% sure, but they probably managed to do this in one of two ways: 1. Manipulate the algorithm to give chronology a big boost or 2. Change the data structure to a cached stack while disallowing newly-calculated posts to overwrite incumbent data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users just want products that work. Over time, the algorithms to determine feed-worthy stories have become more and more accurate. I would find myself sorting by “most recent” very frequently just a year ago, but now I never click the button. If I’m like most users, then they finally found the sweet spot. That sweet spot enabled them to remove clutter from the interface and bridge the gap properly to mobile. Good job Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;navigation-now-follows-real-design-rules&quot;&gt;Navigation now follows real design rules&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all great web application have sidebars. They prove themselves as a great foundation for navigation and widget-style features, but can easily grow cumbersome. Less is usually more, but sometimes the metrics say otherwise. Design ideologies should never get in the way of what works for the end user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new sidebar works very well for a couple reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s not melded into the same background as the rest of the site anymore. The different background creates a contrast that makes the separation feel clean instead of cluttered.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Because it is a sidebar instead of a widget, the common design rule of minimizing the number of container elements is followed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s responsive to the site width. I’d be curious to see what their analytics say about clickthroughs since certain studies have shown that icon-only navigation performs worse than those aided with text. That being said, the effect is dampened since Facebook is already a well-understood product by a majority of its user-base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-does-this-all-mean&quot;&gt;So what does this all mean?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could mean many things. When shown larger posts, people naturally place a higher level of importance on it. Skipping a post without interacting with it feels like a riskier action, and thus, activity on posts further up the feed is likely going to increase while activity on posts further down will decrease. The like button and other assorted actions are no longer blue, but their click-targets have been increased in size. I would place a bet saying this combination results in more clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With forced chronology and the hypothesis mentioned above, I think the end result for most users will be more action on posts right when they create them and less importance or notifications on historically older, but popular posts. It’s more about the “new” than the “popular” and thus you’ll want to keep posting more to garner more likes. Feed that thirst for acceptance amongst your peers! This all fits very neatly into &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57536659-93/zuckerberg-in-10-years-folks-will-share-1000-times-what-they-do-now/&quot;&gt;Mark’s pseudo-Moore’s law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//facebook.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//facebook.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Lets Stop Generalizing</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re better than that. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it quite disingenuous when people give advice to others without a full understanding of their situation. The truly skilled people at conflict resolution are popular for their ability to listen, not just say the right words. But we, the hacker community, have quite a problem. It’s nothing to be ashamed of and it’s completely natural, but it is something that I think we should strive to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We generalize too much. Yahoo recently stated it was not allowing remote work anymore and &lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3453-no-more-remote-work-at-yahoo&quot;&gt;David over at 37Signals&lt;/a&gt; promptly posted his pro-remote working blog article. I respect David immensely and indeed I think overall remote working is a very healthy practice. But let’s get straight to the facts: every process – whether engineering or operational – has both pros and cons. The environment in which it’s applied has significant impact on it’s effectiveness and value-add to the end corporation and user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plain and simple: Remote working did not work at Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t. People familiar with the organization constantly talk about how it led to increased numbers of engineering failures among teams. It drained productivity. It pushed people to be so individualistic that they had no sense of team. Marissa and the executive team at Yahoo aren’t stupid and they deserve a little more compassion from us. We don’t have the metrics they were looking at. We don’t truly understand the Yahoo culture. And even if remote work wasn’t the cause of these problems, stopping it might be part of a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of hammering Yahoo for such a “blind” and “clueless” decision, we should be asking questions to facilitate a better understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why did remote work not work as effectively for a large organization?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What aspects of Yahoo’s culture led to the decline in productivity through remote work?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What data do we assume the executive team was looking at? What should they have been looking at?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not black and white. This is grey. As Nate Silver puts it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/159420411X&quot;&gt;let’s be more like foxes and less like hedgehogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//lets-stop-generalizing.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//lets-stop-generalizing.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
        </channel>
</rss>
