<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
                <title>Zach Tratar</title>
                <description>Ramblings on startups, design, engineering, and political philosophy.</description>
                <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
                <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                
                        <item>
                                <title>My Reply To Senator Feinstein</title>
                                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dianne Feinstein, Senator for California and Head of the Intelligence committee, just sent out an email supporting the NSA surveillance programs. I put her email in the comments section and the PDF she attached can be found &lt;a href=&quot;/files/Feinstein-Chronicle.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to read the full text. This is my reply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senator Feinstein,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all due respect, the beginning line in your second paragraph has already been proven untrue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“First, please be assured that the NSA does not conduct mass surveillance on U.S. citizens.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is well known now that the NSA conducts varies degrees of dragnet data collection. If you are limiting the definition of surveillance to only information that is being looked at &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; by human eyes, then you would be correct. I believe that dragnet data collection is surveillance. My actions, my words, my emotions – everything – is collected. It may not be scrutinized now, but it can be scrutinized later. Any such program removes ones freedom to act – people act different when watched. Usually for the better, I’ll admit, but that is certainly not for the Government to decide. The Sedition acts of the 1800s are a prime example, and I believe this to be of equivalent importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Americans need liberty. The world needs liberty. It is a constitutional requirement that my liberty be protected, and unfortunately, I see it slipping away week by week as select people claim there is no surveillance. How far will you go to fight for my liberty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only ask one thing: please ensure you understand the issue from this perspective – the perspective where definitions are a bit more cloudy than Merriam-Webster. The perspective where pure data collection is a form of surveillance and must be stopped in all forms of dragnet operation. When you vote or propose legislation moving in that direction, you re-affirm a vote from me and thousands of others. When you vote for dragnet data collection, you are voting to limit liberty in all its forms – the antithesis of American pride and power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Precedent is important and I understand the kind of position you’re in is not only complicated, but career-threatening. As the head of the Intelligence community, it may seem that many advocates promoting the same things as me aren’t listening to your side. That might be true, but I sincerely hope that doesn’t lead towards an overall generalization clouding the righteous passions of many citizens. That would be a travesty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want my children to live in a United States of America that promotes peace and, instead of pushing forward the status quo of “us vs them” and “terrorists are inherently evil at birth”, does its best to resolve these issues through intelligent foreign policy and humanitarian aid. I want to live in an America that is a shining city on top of a hill – one that strives to take the high road at every possible moment. Terrorism is a tricky issue – the issue of the century – but it cannot be solved by brute force means. Terrorism is deep-seated anger, hate, and revenge. It is irrational, yet that doesn’t mean it has to be fought with irrational or impure means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founding fathers said that freedom is achievable when liberty is balanced with order. I believe strongly in order, but we also must try different approaches to achieve it and hold each program underneath a spotlight that ranks effectiveness and efficiency. The net loses for Americans through the NSA programs severely outweigh the benefits we derive if, and only if we can maintain order and security through other means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are these other means? I’d like different answers explored through our great legislative and governmental processes. Please make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a good day, Zach&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//feinstein.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//feinstein.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>What I&#39;m Grateful For</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of my friends recently shared a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oHv6vTKD6lg&amp;feature=c4-overview-vl&amp;list=PLzvRx_johoA8PC6S5k5S2SszRQOR8oSEa&quot;&gt;great video about gratitude&lt;/a&gt; and how it correlates with one’s own happiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was driving home last night when I started thinking about this video again. I thought: what am I grateful for? Quite ironically, right when this thought popped in my mind some jagoff cut me off and nearly hit a Prius to my right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not very grateful for that guy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in all seriousness, time to list off some great stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful for genuine people.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s too damned easy to get caught up in fake facades and societal expectations these days. People who challenge this social status quo and simply represent their true selves are the most beautiful of all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to be in a world and nation rich in infrastructure.&lt;/strong&gt; The modern world is amazing. For those lucky enough to be born with access to the internet, modern transportation, complex resource distribution systems, etc, the world is quite literally our playground. We can learn whatever we want, do whatever we want, say whatever we want – build whatever we want. Modern infrastructure has given us the means to attain a level of individual liberty unattainable by our ancestors. Sure, it also comes with societal expectations and imperfect systems, but I think those are merely bumps on a long road; they can be overcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful for the people, both modern and ancient, who built the infrastructure of the world.&lt;/strong&gt; This includes everyone – not just the CEOs of the olden days. I didn’t invent the car, but I get to drive one. I didn’t discover electricity, but I get to show you this set of words because millions of electrons move in unison. I didn’t have to fight for civil rights, but I get to have friends of multiple cultures and races. Every single thing we know and use on this planet was discovered or created by someone just like us. Each invention and piece of forward progress started as as small idea in someone’s mind and grew into something grand. Even though so many problems still exist, so many have been solved. Mad props, old timers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful for everyone fighting to make tomorrow better than today.&lt;/strong&gt; The world presents us many opportunities and it’s not easy to determine how impactful our role truly is. Being self-critical in this environment and taking action to ensure your in the right place requires bravery, pure and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And onto some of the personal stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to have such a loving family.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s always wonderful to talk to my mom, cousins, aunts and uncles. They’re great people and whenever I chat with any of them I feel like I’m home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to have the best friends in the world.&lt;/strong&gt; You all are frigin’ rockstars and have helped me in so many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to live in one of the most beautiful locations I’ve ever known.&lt;/strong&gt; The sunrise peering over the mountains in the bay makes all morning commutes irrationally energizing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to have an awesome set of colleagues.&lt;/strong&gt; Having managed so many parts of a large recruiting process, I’m reminded all the time how unique and rare it is to have this group around me and fighting for the same mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am grateful to be working on something that is truly meaningful.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s all about bringing people together in ways they didn’t believe were possible… helping people find their true home. Home sweet home!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are you grateful for? I’d like to know if you’re willing to share. Tweet it at me below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//grateful.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//grateful.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>PRISM: A Final Blow To Functioning Democracy?</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;In the unlikely chance you found yourself here and have no idea who Ed Snowden is, you need to watch this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/video/2013/jun/09/nsa-whistleblower-edward-snowden-interview-video&quot;&gt;12-minute interview&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t have time? Seriously try and make time. If you care at all about your privacy or the principles upon which America was founded, watch it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prism&quot;&gt;PRISM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The single primary document Ed Snowden leaked outlines an NSA program called “PRISM”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through all of the speculation, it seems the most likely scenario is that PRISM is a data-collection utility. It connects the NSA internal database to specialized, intermediary servers within companies that provide communication services. This includes Google, Facebook, Verizon, Yahoo, AT&amp;amp;T, Apple, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been hearing the Government say over and over that PRISM and these data tools do not “target” American citizens, but according to Edward Snowden the system “ingests everyone by default.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Woah! Those are definitely contradictory statments. Who do we believe? This answer is determined by how we define “target”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s well known amongst the startup and data communities that you want to track almost everything since data storage is cheap. It’s a best practice. Dig a little deeper into news sources and it’s easy to determine that the NSA does, in fact, ingest everything about you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “targeting” language being used by the White House most likely implies how they &lt;em&gt;analyze&lt;/em&gt; the data. But again, it’s never best practice to simply ignore recorded data. Instead, depending on what you’re tracking, you’ll just weight data patterns you’re looking for. Turns out that &lt;em&gt;no one&lt;/em&gt; is exempt from this analysis! The White House claims it does not target Americans simply because they &lt;em&gt;attempt&lt;/em&gt; to only look for foreigners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is a catch: their attempts are failing! Their algorithm to determine whether or not a person is a foreigner only has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informationweek.com/security/privacy/nsa-prism-inside-the-modern-surveillance/240156341&quot;&gt;51% confidence interval&lt;/a&gt;. Just under half the people analyzed by their software are, in fact, American citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we know we’re being recorded and likely analyzed, let’s jump into the high level of what this all means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the_fall_of_functioning_democracy&quot;&gt;The Fall of Functioning Democracy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;History tends to repeat itself as complex sociological and governmental patterns emerge. Even as far &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plato&#39;s_five_regimes&quot;&gt;back as Plato&lt;/a&gt;, there have been theorized cycles for governmental systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although history tends to show that true democracy performs the best, it – like everything – also has its weaknesses. There aren’t many huge points-of-failure in the system, but instead thousands of smaller vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no strong influence or unified government to cover these holes, spreading power can create a slowing of decision-making, inefficiencies in process, and thus both instability and mistrust. Instability leads to a populace that craves security, and as security increases over time, it almost always falls into tyranny. The founding fathers knew this, which led them to say things like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Those who surrender freedom for security will not have, nor do they deserve, either one.” - Benjamin Franklin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This nation was founded upon the primary ideal of freedom. You as a citizen must never passively nor actively be hindered from thinking, acting, and speaking your mind. A functional democracy requires its populace to be both absolutely free and well-informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We the people – we who are entrusted to properly vote in the best legislators – are not informed in the slightest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The US Government’s document classification system was originally created to protect documents that would, if released, harm national security. Unfortunately, it is frequently used to hide unpopular and apparently unconstitutional policies. If people do not have access to this critical information, then they, by definition, cannot be informed to the extent required to make intelligent voting decisions. Instead, the NSA has given themselves a “self-certification that they serve the national interest.” That doesn’t sound like democracy to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I ask you a question: what does it take to speak your mind? What if it’s controversial?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Psychologically, if someone is listening to you and can theoretically use information against you, you are less likely to speak. At that point, &lt;em&gt;you are no longer free&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even if you think you have nothing to hide, &lt;a href=&quot;http://kottke.org/13/06/you-commit-three-felonies-a-day&quot;&gt;think again&lt;/a&gt;. The justice system doesn’t always play nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I know you’re thinking “They’ll still never come after me”. But in that logic lies a tricky problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why_we_should_all_care&quot;&gt;Why We Should All Care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cat is now out of the bag. The public now &lt;em&gt;knows&lt;/em&gt; that the US government is running PRISM-like surveillance programs. Before the leak, using data from programs like this to jail or suppress any individuals’ freedoms would entail high risk. The program could be exposed to the public and the intelligence agency would be under fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But using the data now is far less risky and will thus be used more often. If we allow governmental programs such as PRISM to exist, then we give the intelligence community the go-ahead to use this data in public forum, however that may evolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t predict the future, but someone among the NSA will eventually think about building an API on top of it; someone will think about making the data decentralized; someone will think about making it universally accessible. We are on an extremely slippery slope. Edward Snowden spoke up because he believed that if he didn’t, our losses as a public would be “irrevocable”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irrevocable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This word truly means a lot because it is &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; used when describing software. Snowden himself stated that if he wanted to break down many of the NSA’s systems, he could. PRISM included, considering his unfettered access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is this irrevocable system? I think that the NSA is about to finish a new, highly advanced data collection/analysis system – one that makes PRISM and the other leaked systems look like children’s toys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With their non-democratic self-certification, the NSA is going to continue ingesting every piece of data is can get its hand on. All of your data in one place. It will be spread across numerous locations and have multiple backups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that information is put into the system, it will never cease-to-exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyber-warfare and complex system intrusions are becoming increasingly common. We cannot build perfect security systems – new flaws in seemingly-impervious systems are found all of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When, &lt;em&gt;not if&lt;/em&gt;, there is a massive data leak, what will happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “they’ll still never come after me” mentality is now completely moot; we don’t even know who “they” are. Maybe it’s an identity thief; maybe it’s a foreign government – it could be &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our government is taking these actions in the name of security, but effectively all we’re doing is stockpiling ammo, 99.9% of which can only be shot back at ourselves. We then put that ammo behind a shoddy wall for safekeeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quite obviously, this does not make us more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are we sure we want to live in that world? Are we sure our children and grand-children will want to live in that world?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s completely possible that we are making that choice right now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//prism.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//prism.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Training like Tesla: An Experiment of the Mind</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m going to undergo an experiment with which I am the test subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea manifested while I was reading ”&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/My-Inventions-Autobiography-introduction-ebook/dp/B004W48LAG&quot;&gt;My Inventions: The autobiography of Nikola Tesla&lt;/a&gt;”. The man is believed among scientific minds to have been savant-like and it certainly shows in his writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easy to make assumptions as to how an engineer could write, but Nikola defies those assumptions. He defies the standards to which people apply him, and by all counts he did that in absolutely every field in his life. Almost no human to have ever lived has accomplished as much as Nikola.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any person who exhibits abilities seemingly beyond our grasp, we begin to wonder how they got there in the first place. What made them great? Did they eat their wheaties? Did they go through special training? Were they born with it? Entire debates have forged through history around nature versus nurture for the explicit purpose of understanding what makes one human being more productive to society than another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the_power_of_imagination&quot;&gt;The power of imagination&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here, at least in the reference of Nikola, we have data. Well… we have what he wrote down, which we can only assume to be as honest as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What made Nikola great was his precise and grandiose imagination. He grew up with an intense visual imagination that tormented him when he was unable to control it. It would present itself forcibly unto his mind when he was trying to interact in the real world. He grew up without confidence in himself thinking that this was a shackle destined to cripple his life-long worth and validity. But he learned to control it. And for all the pain he suffered, the sheer beauty of the upside is hard to match. I could do no better to describe it than he:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I soon discovered that my best comfort was attained if I simply went on in my vision further and further, getting new impressions all the time, and so I began to travel; of course, in my mind. Every night, (and sometimes during the day), when alone, I would start on my journeys – see new places, cities and countries; live there, meet people and make friendship and acquaintances&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This I did constantly until I was about seventeen, when my thoughts turned seriously to invention. Then I observed to my delight that I could visualize with the greatest facility. I need no models, drawings or experiments. I could picture them all as real in my mind… I do not rush into actual work. When I get an idea, I start at once building it up in my imagination. I change the construction, make improvements and operate the device in my mind. It is absolutely immaterial to me whether I run my turbine in thought or test it in my shop.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;- Nikola Tesla&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an engineer or “builder” you’re probably feeling jealous right about now; or maybe you think he is crazy. Either way, this guy’s imagination was a private sandbox with zero limitations. It emulated reality so accurately that he could invent and discover in ways that others could not do in hundreds of lifetimes. The electricity powering your screen right now was surely, at least at point, transmitted as alternating current. Nikola did that. Let’s also not forget about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pbs.org/tesla/ll/ll_whoradio.html&quot;&gt;Radio&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fi.edu/learn/case-files/tesla/motor.html&quot;&gt;Electric Motor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is_this_an_innate_talent_or_is_it_developed&quot;&gt;Is this an innate talent or is it developed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyday tasks are not usually intense enough to put stress on the imagination. They are relatively easy and entail things like planning out the next couple minutes of your day, writing short emails, or remembering where the checkbook is located.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But every so often we all face complicated problems. They start out simple enough and as higher-level goals, but at some point, as you mentally break them down, you hit a large wall. The clarity with which you can visualize, plan, and think is drastically reduced and you bring the process into the physical world through writing or drawing. UX Designers wireframe, engineers whiteboard or jump into code, interior designers start grabbing fabric samples, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t usually question this natural wall. But change your perspective on imagination for a moment and think of it &lt;em&gt;purely&lt;/em&gt; as a skill you can develop. Just as you can rate your other abilities – maybe you’re a great coder or orator – rate your imagination. How &lt;em&gt;useful&lt;/em&gt; is it to you right now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, it seems the utility provided by one’s imagination is in direct correlation with this wall’s location. The more in-depth you can think with absolute clarity before ramming into the barrier, the better use you will get out of your imagination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, we want to learn to move our wall; we want to push it further and further, inch by inch, until its limiting effects are diminished and we gain a newfound freedom in our own imagination. Nikola’s wall was miles and miles away during his peak but he admits to not having the same abilities as a child, so it seems that this is an ability one can foster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps Nikola’s mental travels, inventions, and constant use of his imagination trained him. Perhaps those experiences pushed his wall further and further until he was left with a giant sandbox. That’s the experiment I will attempt to undergo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building_a_sandbox&quot;&gt;Building a sandbox&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, I am not attempting to say that I am more fit to do this than anyone else. In fact, my goal is to “prove” the opposite: I want to see if this ability is attainable by anyone. I want to experience the upside: a truly lean process of ideation and iteration that removes the physical complexities (one that would make &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Blank&quot;&gt;Steven Blank&lt;/a&gt; proud).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I find it easy to rate, with precision, my ability to imagine &lt;em&gt;things&lt;/em&gt;; I think I know where my wall is located. As such, I’m going to do my best to track any progress I make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll train the same way Nikola did: first imagining things I’ve already seen and places I’ve already been. My childhood home, neighborhood, travel destinations, products I use, objects, etc. I’m going to imagine the people I’ve met, the sounds I’ve heard, and even the emotions I’ve felt. Following that I’ll see if I can go further down the path of creating new experiences and inventions. Specifically, the idea is to create increasingly complex scenes and visualize increasingly complex problems until the wall is inches away. At that point, the test is whether or not the wall can be moved and if it will stay once moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nikola traversed the worlds of physics and electromagnetism in his mind. He manifested his findings into real world developments. I hope the same can be done for the digital world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more data, the better the experiment: If anyone is interested in embarking on this journey/test with me, let me know (email, twitter, facebook – they all work). I’m beyond excited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p class=&#39;small&#39;&gt;
	&lt;img alt=&#39;Marc thinks I will go insane&#39; src=&#39;https://dl.dropboxusercontent.com/u/5631577/blog/Screen%20Shot%202013-04-12%20at%203.27.01%20PM.png&#39; /&gt;
	Thank you to those who helped review this post: Eric, Andrew, Vinay, Chris, Rajaishi, Raj, Dino, and Nik

	... and Marc
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//tesla.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//tesla.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>The New Facebook News Feed: A UX Breakdown</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet is blowing up with sensationalized articles on the new &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/about/newsfeed&quot;&gt;Facebook News Feed&lt;/a&gt;. I’m not a fan of that, so instead let’s talk about design principles and user behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the_stories_are_frigin_huge&quot;&gt;The “Stories” are frigin HUGE&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the biggest surprise in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a couple emotions you want to achieve in feeds. The first is zen – it’s calming to get lost and just keep scrolling. The second is usually balanced chaos. The more stuff you see, the more active the site feels. Facebook still has zen, but the chaos seems to have been thrown out in favor of further simplicity. It takes more scrolling to see less items, but nothing is fighting for your attention. Instead of thinking, you’re either looking at the top most “story” or you’re scrolling to the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mobile works the same way. As you move from phone to computer the experience won’t be nearly as jarring. If the feeds are identical on mobile and desktop, I wouldn’t be surprised if they release a feature later to sync your spot on the feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this_is_facebooks_biggest_change_yet_but_the_risk_is_being_overestimated&quot;&gt;This is Facebook’s biggest change yet, but the risk is being overestimated&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/07/facebook-risks-it-all/&quot;&gt;Techcrunch’s article&lt;/a&gt; says this is their most risky change yet. After the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Facebook_Beacon&quot;&gt;Beacon&lt;/a&gt; incident years ago, Facebook has become a more data-driven company. They have a huge data research team pillaging their logs to track user behavior. Is this is a big change? You betcha… it’s the home page! On web applications with a news feed system, a heavy majority of all interaction is done on the home page. Is this a risky choice? Not really. They’re releasing is slowly and watching the data. Risk is mitigated as they iterate – and they will. Compared to the risk presented when Facebook opened up their &lt;a href=&quot;http://money.cnn.com/2007/05/24/technology/facebook.fortune/&quot;&gt;first developer APIs&lt;/a&gt;, this is nothing (and it’s only because of the data).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sorting_has_been_optimized_out&quot;&gt;Sorting has been optimized out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the feed is being changed to a combination of “new” and “popular”. This is not done very often. Facebook can only do this effectively because their average user comes back to the site multiple times a day. This also means that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://edgerank.net/&quot;&gt;demonized edge-rank algorithm&lt;/a&gt; is probably taking more of a backseat or was altered substantially. Changing an algorithm from being entirely score based to purely chronologically dependent isn’t easy at scale. I can’t be 100% sure, but they probably managed to do this in one of two ways: 1. Manipulate the algorithm to give chronology a big boost or 2. Change the data structure to a cached stack while disallowing newly-calculated posts to overwrite incumbent data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Users just want products that work. Over time, the algorithms to determine feed-worthy stories have become more and more accurate. I would find myself sorting by “most recent” very frequently just a year ago, but now I never click the button. If I’m like most users, then they finally found the sweet spot. That sweet spot enabled them to remove clutter from the interface and bridge the gap properly to mobile. Good job Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;navigation_now_follows_real_design_rules&quot;&gt;Navigation now follows real design rules&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost all great web application have sidebars. They prove themselves as a great foundation for navigation and widget-style features, but can easily grow cumbersome. Less is usually more, but sometimes the metrics say otherwise. Design ideologies should never get in the way of what works for the end user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new sidebar works very well for a couple reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s not melded into the same background as the rest of the site anymore. The different background creates a contrast that makes the separation feel clean instead of cluttered.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Because it is a sidebar instead of a widget, the common design rule of minimizing the number of container elements is followed.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;It’s responsive to the site width. I’d be curious to see what their analytics say about clickthroughs since certain studies have shown that icon-only navigation performs worse than those aided with text. That being said, the effect is dampened since Facebook is already a well-understood product by a majority of its user-base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so_what_does_this_all_mean&quot;&gt;So what does this all mean?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It could mean many things. When shown larger posts, people naturally place a higher level of importance on it. Skipping a post without interacting with it feels like a riskier action, and thus, activity on posts further up the feed is likely going to increase while activity on posts further down will decrease. The like button and other assorted actions are no longer blue, but their click-targets have been increased in size. I would place a bet saying this combination results in more clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With forced chronology and the hypothesis mentioned above, I think the end result for most users will be more action on posts right when they create them and less importance or notifications on historically older, but popular posts. It’s more about the “new” than the “popular” and thus you’ll want to keep posting more to garner more likes. Feed that thirst for acceptance amongst your peers! This all fits very neatly into &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57536659-93/zuckerberg-in-10-years-folks-will-share-1000-times-what-they-do-now/&quot;&gt;Mark’s pseudo-Moore’s law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//facebook.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//facebook.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Lets Stop Generalizing</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re better than that. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find it quite disingenuous when people give advice to others without a full understanding of their situation. The truly skilled people at conflict resolution are popular for their ability to listen, not just say the right words. But we, the hacker community, have quite a problem. It’s nothing to be ashamed of and it’s completely natural, but it is something that I think we should strive to improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We generalize too much. Yahoo recently stated it was not allowing remote work anymore and &lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com/svn/posts/3453-no-more-remote-work-at-yahoo&quot;&gt;David over at 37Signals&lt;/a&gt; promptly posted his pro-remote working blog article. I respect David immensely and indeed I think overall remote working is a very healthy practice. But let’s get straight to the facts: every process – whether engineering or operational – has both pros and cons. The environment in which it’s applied has significant impact on it’s effectiveness and value-add to the end corporation and user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plain and simple: Remote working did not work at Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn’t. People familiar with the organization constantly talk about how it led to increased numbers of engineering failures among teams. It drained productivity. It pushed people to be so individualistic that they had no sense of team. Marissa and the executive team at Yahoo aren’t stupid and they deserve a little more compassion from us. We don’t have the metrics they were looking at. We don’t truly understand the Yahoo culture. And even if remote work wasn’t the cause of these problems, stopping it might be part of a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of hammering Yahoo for such a “blind” and “clueless” decision, we should be asking questions to facilitate a better understanding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why did remote work not work as effectively for a large organization?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;What aspects of Yahoo’s culture led to the decline in productivity through remote work?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;What data do we assume the executive team was looking at? What should they have been looking at?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not black and white. This is grey. As Nate Silver puts it: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/159420411X&quot;&gt;let’s be more like foxes and less like hedgehogs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//lets-stop-generalizing.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//lets-stop-generalizing.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>New Years Resolutions</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve never made new years resolutions before, so this is a completely new experience. A quote I recently read inspired me to make this list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our own life is the instrument with which we experiment with the truth” - Thich Nhat Hang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;read_write_and_learn_more&quot;&gt;Read, write, and learn more&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago I got a Kindle Paperwhite and rediscovered reading as a hobby. First I dove into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Cloud-Atlas-Novel-David-Mitchell/dp/0375507256&quot;&gt;Cloud Atlas&lt;/a&gt;, a truly unique novel whose plot spans multiple lifetimes. I had never “gotten lost” in a book before, so reading CA was such a unique experience that I picked up an urge to keep reading. So far, it’s been great! Next up on my reading list are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Signal-Noise-Many-Predictions-Fail/dp/159420411X/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1357072711&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=signal+and+noise&quot;&gt;The Signal and the Noise&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Confessions-Public-Speaker-English/dp/1449301959/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1357072741&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=confessions+of+a+public+speaker&quot;&gt;Confessions of a Public Speaker&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a couple documentaries – my favorites being &lt;a href=&quot;http://video.pbs.org/video/1312522241/&quot;&gt;Becoming Human&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://topdocumentaryfilms.com/guns-germs-and-steel/&quot;&gt;Guns, Germs, and Steel&lt;/a&gt;. These two documentaries together tell a very wholistic story of humanity. Really fascinating stuff. I’m definitely going to write a blog post about those two next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the course of reading and watching, I’ve also started taking notes on everything I learn. Hopefully this will turn into better developed thoughts and more writing! My goal for 2013 is to read 2 books, watch 8 documentaries, and write 2 blog posts every month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;become_a_morning_person&quot;&gt;Become a morning person&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently a night owl. It’s likely a habit I developed through Computer Engineering MPs or in High School from late night gaming sessions. Gotta love being a nerd. Lately though, I’ve noticed that whenever I can wake up earlier in the morning – usually by luck – I’m much more prepared to take on the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startup cultures aren’t very strict with morning work schedules. Without outside factors forcing me to wake up earlier, I’m going to create one through this new years resolution! In addition to waking up earlier, I’m going to try and get 8 hours of sleep a night. That’s gonna be hard to pull off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;explore_new_activities&quot;&gt;Explore new activities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People commonly refer to maintaining a balance between mind, body, and spirit. My currently lifestyle is 100% mind and to hell with the rest. I know it’s cliche, but it’s time to start working out again! The goal is 2 times a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not much of a spiritual person, but I think there is a silver-lining in many practices normally considered spiritual. After reading both &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Sacred-Hoops-Spiritual-Lessons-Hardwood/dp/1401308813&quot;&gt;Sacred Hoops&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Steve-Jobs-Walter-Isaacson/dp/1451648537/ref=sr_1_1?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1357072868&amp;sr=1-1&amp;keywords=steve+jobs&quot;&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve become interested in Zen meditation. I don’t see it as a way to reach enlightenment or anything, but just as a way to organize thoughts and gain an inner sense of calmness. When I’m in that calm, brainstorming state (which right now only happens randomly), I get my best ideas. If I can start inducing that state on demand I think I can be more productive. Goal: play around with meditation. If I like it, 2-3 times a week sounds good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really want to travel more and explore cultures that I have no connection with. An all-out road trip throughout an entire continent or country sounds exciting… probably China, Brazil, or Western Europe. Not sure which yet – anyone have recommendations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;material_lifestyle_improvements&quot;&gt;Material lifestyle improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People give a bad rap to goals that involve material goods, but screw it, I’m putting them in here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to finally be getting a car and, at some point, I want to move into my own place downtown SF. I’ve only experienced living in a city for 3 days before, but even from that show time I could tell I was a city person. The new apartment will also be the first time I get real furniture and not just the cheapest thing I can find at IKEA (No hate. IKEA has served me well in the past).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that’s set up, I want to rig the apartment with tech. &lt;a href=&quot;http://arduino.cc/blog/category/hacks/home-hacks/&quot;&gt;Automate tasks with arduinos&lt;/a&gt;… maybe a Rube Goldberg machine to make breakfast? Haha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright… now I officially have a list of things to which I can hold myself accountable. Blog post #1 &lt;em&gt;done&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//new-years.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//new-years.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Passion Finder</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;I tend to think about random web ideas quite frequently, so here goes a brain dump!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the highest of levels, humanity thrives around individuals finding their passion and taking a “deep dive” into that area. People’s passion often brings people together around ideas and action. Martin Luther King Jr, The Wright Brothers, Steve Jobs… you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are many people out there who can’t find their own passion. It’s hard to just sit down at a desk or on a couch and think “What am I passionate about?” People always say we live in an era of information overload, but why is this question so difficult to answer? Information overload causes people to shut off their minds to too many things. Most people don’t have enough holistic information on any given subject to discover that it is their passion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And even those who have a sense of direction don’t always have the guts to go out and invest large amounts of time. First, you have to get off the couch. Then, you usually have to buy supplies/equipment. Then, you have to work your ass off. During this process, you’re expectations will be much higher than your actual performance, and you’re likely to lose interest. The select few who overcome each and every obstacle - take each punch as it is thrown - will be those who can truly say they are passionate about something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets_find_a_solution&quot;&gt;Let’s find a solution&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a big problem. A solution at scale will not only better individuals lives, but also entire communities, nations, and industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to focus on a single solution: Mentorship (but not in the traditional sense!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentorship is powerful, as it drastically increases your chances of overcoming every single barrier mentioned above. It’s a flexible solution to an extremely dynamic problem. Jane thinks she is passionate about bird-watching and Bill thinks his calling is Nano-robotics. Both can find mentors. Jane can’t seem to find the right equipment for bird watching. Bill started researching Nano-robotics, but isn’t confident that his background in Analog Signal Processing gives him real potential in the field. Mentors have the indivudual capability to assess these problems and figure out solutions: Jane should buy a pair of WP Naturescape Binoculars and Bill should do selective research on nano-scale signal interference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the technology-driven mentorship space is ripe for innovation. It’s honestly pretty easy to monetize and is - most importantly - good for humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fixing_one_problem_can_solve_another&quot;&gt;Fixing one problem can solve another&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mentorship is a great solution to this passion problem… but it, itself, needs fixing. Luckily, it seems easier to fix! 2-for-1… woot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s outline the problems with mentorship:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to find a person passionate about a specific subject, let alone a mentor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being a mentor is a big hassle. Subject areas that are less common will have mentors who usually have less and less time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentorship is an unstructured process, and expectations are hard to figure out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People mentor others they already like and no one else. Mentoring strangers? Pay me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so we need to build a product that matches people in a reasonably unstructured fashion around their passions, but is also non-committal. The product also needs to represent each individual in a personal way and get them talking, so they are more open to mentorship in the future. In addition, some sort of reward will get more people talking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great. I’ve got a job, but I also work on pet projects. This is one of them. If you want to be a part, email me at ztratar@gmail.com and let’s get cracking.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//passion-finder.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//passion-finder.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>The American Spirit: Who Bears Responsibility</title>
                                <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;the_spirit_of_building_anew&quot;&gt;The Spirit of Building Anew&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Americans have grown up under the ideology that we all take responsibility for our own actions - but do we?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Responsibility is perceived to be this looming hulk of a beast by many, and indeed I’ve ran into people who blatantly say “I don’t like or want responsibility”. The thought of you being responsible for something generates stress. And we’re all human - we all succumb to a bit of stress now and then. But where are all of the people saying “Bring it on!”? (and no, I’m not talking about cheerleaders)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine led to me start watching debates ran by Intelligence Squared. I’ve watched a couple recently and two have stood out: “Is Big Government Stifling The American Spirit?” and “Does China Do Capitalism Better Than America?” These debates were fantastic and display both sides of the story. I highly recommend watching them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did these two debates get at exactly? How did they overlap? They both talked about how this nation was founded and the principles that guided its success. There is no single solution to anything, so I took most opinions with a grain of salt, but there was one glaring point that kept being repeated: “The US isn’t what it used to be!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No… really? Of course it’s not what it used to be. Things change. I’m an entrepreneur and an engineer, so I love the way technology has pushed this country and the world in my lifetime. It’s clear that morals, standards, and etiquette has changed over the years. A stark difference I don’t necessarily enjoy to observe has to do with social responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m young and didn’t live in the 19th century or the roaring 20’s, and indeed there are few centenarians (old people) even alive today who can fact check, but history books do make it seem like this “can do” attitude was more prevalent back in the day. The US was the vibrant nation filled with eager and excited people out to fix the world. We still have this trait lingering around, but even in Silicon Valley, it’s common to find those who just don’t care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what caused all of this? I have a theory, but it goes against most of my own economic and political beliefs. What I’m about to discuss isn’t an end-all be-all. It is a theory based on both macro-economic and individualistic observations, take it as such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the_theory&quot;&gt;The Theory&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the Government’s prevalence in our day-to-day lives has shifted the average burden of all responsibility off of the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I think we have a huge government in the US? I don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I think big government is even a necessarily bad thing? Not always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I think the thought of larger government decreases social responsibility off of individuals? Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s also define big government. I want to define it in an emotional sense, rather than a number-crunch. There are metrics that can argue nearly any side of any debate if you look hard enough… data overload. Even if the government isn’t big right now, does it feel big? Lots of people are talking about big government, so maybe that even contributes to our feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When most see something wrong, whether it be discrimination, regulation, crime rates, corruption, etc, the initial reaction is the blame the government. We no longer, as in the 1800’s, carry around pistols and protect our own neighborhoods. We no longer gather in droves like those who did for Martin Luther King. We no longer act as individuals for causes greater than ourselves - we just blame our politicians who are doing it poorly for us. It’s become our natural tendency to blame someone else and to push responsibility off of ourselves. We’ve become docile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’m not saying to go buy a pistol and go wild, wild, west on your jerk-face neighbor (Seriously don’t… by the way). If you think education needs help, go out and tutor kids, donate to schools, support local teachers, and get others to help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is_it_bad_parenting&quot;&gt;Is it Bad Parenting?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As others take care of issues for us, we ultimately just go with the flow. It’s like children who have parents who clean their room. If they stop cleaning the room, it gets messy. Then the kid complains that it isn’t clean. Clean it up yourself, kiddo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, that is ideological. It just won’t work. Since the kid is used to having his room cleaned, he now demands his room be cleaned or he’ll vote in new parents! You can’t starve the beast - er, starve the parents - as making them weak will also ruin their ability to take their kid to school. It’s an evil cycle, and the problem is not fundamentally with the parents; it’s with the kid. The kid who wants the new shiny toy but doesn’t want to do the chores. The kid who cries when he scrapes his face, but refuses to wear a helmet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kid needs to grow up, solve his own problems, and be willing to help the other kid across the street. He’s a smart kid… luckily. He’s a free kid… luckily. And this kid has the potential to fix the world if he chooses to do so. So is big government stifling the American Spirit? No. It’s likely just us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;digression__copout&quot;&gt;Digression / Cop-out&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll digress with an excerpt from John F. Kennedy’s inaugural speech:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In your hands, my fellow citizens, more than in mine, will rest the final success or failure of our course. Since this country was founded, each generation of Americans has been summoned to give testimony to its national loyalty. The graves of young Americans who answered the call to service surround the globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the trumpet summons us again - not as a call to bear arms, though arms we need; not as a call to battle, though embattled we are - but a call to bear the burden of a long twilight struggle, year in and year out, “rejoicing in hope, patient in tribulation” - a struggle against the common enemies of man: tyranny, poverty, disease, and war itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we forge against these enemies a grand and global alliance, North and South, East and West, that can assure a more fruitful life for all mankind? Will you join in that historic effort?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the long history of the world, only a few generations have been granted the role of defending freedom in its hour of maximum danger. I do not shank from this responsibility - I welcome it. I do not believe that any of us would exchange places with any other people or any other generation. The energy, the faith, the devotion which we bring to this endeavour will light our country and all who serve it - and the glow from that fire can truly light the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so, my fellow Americans: ask not what your country can do for you - ask what you can do for your country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My fellow citizens of the world: ask not what America will do for you, but what together we can do for the freedom of man.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, whether you are citizens of America or citizens of the world, ask of us the same high standards of strength and sacrifice which we ask of you. With a good conscience our only sure reward, with history the final judge of our deeds, let us go forth to lead the land we love, asking His blessing and His help, but knowing that here on earth God’s work must truly be our own.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//american-spirit.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//american-spirit.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Successful Entrepreneurs Build From The Heart</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;The tech industry is a haphazard, chaotic scramble of companies, capital, and recruiters. Among this craze, I have been lucky enough to meet, and in some cases befriend, some very talented people - from VCs and CEOs to contractors trying to get their foot in the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one characteristic that seems to be very polarized in the valley: heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that’s what I want to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I say that someone has heart, what I mean is that they are seriously emotionally involved with their work. They do what they do for a reason, and that reason is not encompassed solely by logic. It’s that purely human urge to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe heart is the essential ingredient to a Silicon Valley “success story.” People either have it or they don’t, and after talking to someone for 5 minutes, it’s usually obvious where they stand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building from the heart means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If out looking for a job, you don’t choose a company because you want to network with the founders or get a fantastic salary. You choose a company because what you’ll be working on blows your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get excited every time you pitch your product/idea because you re-realize that what you’re doing is easily worth the hardship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When your friends say “Why do you work so much?”, you think “work…? This is play.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do whatever it takes to see the vision become reality - whether that means learning to pitch or learning to program. (Or squatting at AOL, like my friend Eric).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get impatient. Not because you’re directly mad at yourself or others, but because the damn thing isn’t built yet and you want to use it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When someone tries to poach you, you mirror it back! If they want to work with you, they better join you, not vice-versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have heart, it’s my opinion that you’re not working on the right idea. If you do, keep doing what you’re doing and luck will find it’s way to you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://localhost:4000//successful-entrepreneurs.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//successful-entrepreneurs.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
        </channel>
</rss>
