<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
        <channel>
                <title>Zach Tratar</title>
                <description>Ramblings on startups, design, engineering, and political philosophy.</description>
                <link>http://zachtratar.com</link>
                <atom:link href="http://zachtratar.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Declaration of a Global Ethic</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot lately about the bitter division in US politics and how the internet is making everyone an extremist. I can’t help but think civilization, in many ways, has all been here before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When online, many people treat each other quite poorly – we label the “us” vs “them”, choose condemnation over collaboration, and mimc other’s negative behaviors into a collective death spiral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What could make people act nicer? What has historically done so?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our weakening institutions are of interest, especially institutionalized religion. I don’t believe people need religion to be good, but perhaps some people do need religion to default to good behavior. Perhaps the weekly jolt of indoctrination makes them habitually more likely to practice goodness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-golden-rule&quot;&gt;The Golden Rule&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Do unto others as you would have them do unto you.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What you wish upon others, you wish upon yourself.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;hundreds&lt;/em&gt; of variations – in essentially every religion in the world, the “Golden Rule” pops up early in its history. Perhaps we’ve all been here before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps as the first tribes of people came into contact with others, their differences led them to amplify their division, create enemies, and promote destruction. And then, spread across the world in hundreds of different ways, maybe we learned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is the Golden Rule a “counter-algorithm” to mitigate our tribal weaknesses?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;declaration-of-a-global-ethic&quot;&gt;Declaration of a Global Ethic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While rabbit-holing around the rule’s origins, I came across the 1993 &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20130411195746/http://www.parliamentofreligions.org/_includes/FCKcontent/File/TowardsAGlobalEthic.pdf&quot;&gt;“Declaration of a Global Ethic”&lt;/a&gt; – a document espousing what we as individuals in society must do to heal and make progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a collaboration of 143 different religious leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a section I like in particular:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are interdependent. Each of us depends on the well-being of the whole, and so we have respect for the community of living beings, for people, animals, and plants, and for the preservation of Earth, the air, water and soil.
We take individual responsibility for all we do. All our decisions, actions, and failures to act have consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We must treat others as we wish others to treat us. We make a commitment to respect life and dignity, individuality and diversity, so that every person is treated humanely, without exception. We must have patience and acceptance. We must be able to forgive, learning form the past but never allowing ourselves to be enslaved by memories of hate. Opening our hearts to one another, we must sink our narrow differences for the cause of world community, practicing a culture of solidarity and relatedness.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We consider humankind a family. We must strive to be kind and generous. We must not live for ourselves alone, but should also serve others, never forgetting the children, the aged, the poor, the suffering, the disabled, the refugees and the lonely. No person should ever be considered or treated as a second-class citizen, or be exploited in any way whatsoever. There should be equal partnership between men and women. We must not commit any kind of sexual immorality. We must put behind us all forms of domination or abuse.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We commit ourselves to a culture of non-violence, respect, justice, and peace. We shall not oppress, injure, torture, or kill other human beings, forsaking violence as a means of settling differences.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We must strive for a just social and economic order, in which everyone has an equal chance to reach full potential as a human being. We must speak and act truthfully and with compassion, dealing fairly with all, and avoiding prejudice and hatred. We must not steal. We must move beyond the dominance of greed for power, prestige, money, and consumption to make a just and peaceful world.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Earth cannot be changed for the better unless the consciousness of individuals is changed first. We pledge to increase our awareness by disciplining our minds, by meditation, by prayer, or by positive thinking. Without risk and a readiness to sacrifice there can be no fundamental change in our situation. Therefore we commit ourselves to this global ethic, to understanding one another, and to socially beneficial, peace-fostering, and nature-friendly ways of life.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We invite all people, whether religious or not, to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we all followed the above principles, the world would look a heck of a lot different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Someday we’ll get there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//declaration-of-a-global-ethic.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//declaration-of-a-global-ethic.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Voter Fraud? GOP Claim Quick Debunk</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2009 I founded by first startup, a political polling via text message company, while a freshman in college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We eventually gained some steam and were able to get an introduction to this asshole named &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jmclghln?lang=en&quot;&gt;John McLaughlin&lt;/a&gt;, one of the Republican Party’s “top pollsters”. He offered to buy out our company for the GOP (which we refused). As a silly freshman does in 2009, I decided to add him on Facebook back then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward to today and he’s literally Donald Trump’s go-to pollster. I’m one degree from him, and have seen him change over the last 10 years from “polling to get data” to “polling as propaganda.” The propaganda that comes out of his facebook is usually laughable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But now it has become sinister.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays we have the entire GOP political apparatus claiming there was widespread voter fraud, shaking the faith Americans have in democracy itself. After Trump’s loss in the election and his subsequent claims of fraud, Republican’s belief in US elections has dropped to under 15%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is that? They’re all over Facebook. They’re eating up the trash that John McLaughlin and his GOP cronies serve up on a daily basis. When I log in to Facebook, guess what I see?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/2020-11-10-voter-fraud/1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On his twitter, the post has 45 retweets alone. It’s spreading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;18-million-ghost-voters-sounds-scary&quot;&gt;1.8 million ghost voters! Sounds scary!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a big number, and of course, as an American, I am genuinely desiring of a legitimate election. So despite Trump losing every single voter fraud court case thus far, I wanted to check in on this 1.8 million ghost voter story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is from “The Washington Times,” which is pulling the Judicial Watch “study”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/2020-11-10-voter-fraud/2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you then click into the study, you got to the Judicial Watch’s press release. Yet another link then brings you to the study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here it is. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judicialwatch.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/10/Judicial-Watch-Voter-Roll-Study-Oct-2020-1.pdf&quot;&gt;You can see the study in its entirety&lt;/a&gt;. It’s literally just a spreadsheet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/2020-11-10-voter-fraud/3.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;County by county, Judicial Watch shows where the voter registrations are higher than the number of potential voters. Eek! And that thus there were “ghost voters” — voters who don’t exist. Fraudulent ballots.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They then add up all these overages to get a total number of &lt;em&gt;1.8 million v&lt;/em&gt;oters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the entire analysis is comically fragile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weakness-1-cvap-already-has-quite-a-lot-of-error&quot;&gt;Weakness #1: CVAP already has quite a lot of error.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CVAP (Census Voting Age Population) estimate for 2018 is based on the old census’ population estimate of the area, and then projects how may people in that population &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be voting eligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The estimate is controversial because i&lt;a href=&quot;https://campaignlegal.org/update/census-bureaus-citizenship-data-collection-misguided-and-harmful&quot;&gt;t’s often inaccurate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conservatively, the CVAP already has a +-5% error rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weakness-2-populations-in-decline--voters-who-havent-changed-their-locations&quot;&gt;Weakness #2: Populations in decline → voters who haven’t changed their locations.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the top 3 counties (Lowdes, Macon, Wilcox), let’s dig in further. Here are their populations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/2020-11-10-voter-fraud/4.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/2020-11-10-voter-fraud/5.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/2020-11-10-voter-fraud/6.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notice anything?&lt;/em&gt; They are all going through population declines at roughly 5.2% per 5 years!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When people move away, they can stay registered to vote in an old location, thus further inflating the ratio’s error.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This alone can add another ~5% of error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you may think — but Lowdes is at 129%! Even with 10% what about the other 19% who voted?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this is where it all just goes from weak calculations to intentional propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;weakness-3-the-entire-study-says-nothing-about-voting-in-fact-the-math-works-out&quot;&gt;Weakness #3: The entire study says &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; about voting. In fact, the math works out!**&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The study measures registered voters over an estimate of total potential voters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It says nothing about the actual votes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we actually wanted to find evidence of ghost voters, we’d want to see that the # of votes was higher than the overall voting population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Lowndes you have a voting population estimate of 7,890, given the CVAP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many votes were there in Lowndes? Let’s look at Bloomberg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/2020-11-10-voter-fraud/7.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 6,830 votes, giving an estimated voter turnout of 86%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, that does sound high! But it isn’t over 100%, and all of the sudden the entire claim of “ghost voters” falls apart. The evidence just isn’t there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;want-to-know-the-best-part&quot;&gt;Want to know the best part?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s look how these counties break down racially, using &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sos.alabama.gov/alabama-votes/voter/election-data&quot;&gt;Alabama’s own census data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lowndes is 74% Black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Macon is 83% Black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wilcox is 70% Black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What happened this year? Black voters came out and made their voice heard.&lt;/strong&gt; And the GOP just can’t believe that — after all, Trump is “the best President for Blacks in the history of the United States”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead what does the GOP do? They lie. They mislead. They spread propaganda, and power-hungry assholes like John McLaughlin do their bidding. They don’t even care to do the research anymore when a “top pollster” decides to share a single spreadsheet with weak analysis and the most politicized, anti-American message possible: mass voter fraud — “illegal votes” — without real evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Americans, this should concern all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Radicalized Trump supporters believe these things without doing research, because it appears as though a “Real News Source” like the Washington Times, with “Judicial Watch” did the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is “The Washington Times”? Although you can’t tell on the website, it’s a conservative “news outlet” founded by Sun Myung Moon, who claimed to be a messiah. Seriously.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is Judicial Watch? Turns out it’s a conservative activist group, known for strategically promoting conspiracy theories. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Judicial_Watch&quot;&gt;Take a look yourself.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We must be vigilant in the days ahead as propaganda spreads like wildfire across Facebook. We need a peaceful transition power now more than ever, and it’s up to us (unfortunately) to call out the propaganda in the social sphere as the courts halt it in the judiciary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//voter-fraud-debunk.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//voter-fraud-debunk.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Introducing BillionaireBoard</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you ever think about what you’d do with a billion dollars?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not talking about what you’d choose to buy. Instead, which of the world’s problems would you try to solve? You could start entire companies, hire people, conduct mass-scale research, and maybe — just maybe — even influence Governments 🤯.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty fun to think about, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill Gates over the last couple decades has focused on the eradication of malaria, low cost toilets, safe nuclear power, and more. After seeing some of the media around these innovations a while back, I became curious: what are all the other billionaires up to?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hours and hours of boring research commenced — tax forms, foundation websites, news articles, and even lawsuits. Although major donations were happening every week, building my personal research spreadsheet became an absolute nightmare… and I was still on my 2nd billionaire!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are ~2,200 billionaires in the world, by the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan for research had totally failed, but my questions still felt important:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is donating &amp;amp; impact investing into what? How much?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are they giving a lot? What about compared to their lifetime giving, or their net worth?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are these projects, exactly? Are they going well, and is the money being spent well?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-can-the-public-help&quot;&gt;How can the public help?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I was thinking about these questions, some tweets rolled into my feed — Mark Zuckerberg had just donated a couple hundred million dollars to medical research. What did people do? They mostly took the opportunity to yell at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many people understandably default to anger in our age of mass inequality, it’s also true that Mark has a lifetime goal to “cure all diseases” and &lt;a href=&quot;https://billionaireboard.com/billionaires/mark-zuckerberg&quot;&gt;has pledged to donate 99% of his wealth&lt;/a&gt; to take on the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billionaires don’t always have all the answers themselves. They contract with research institutes, think tanks, and other institutions to help them answer their fundamental question: “How do I spend this money effectively?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Jeff Bezos famously &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/jeffbezos/status/875418348598603776?lang=en&quot;&gt;posted a “request for ideas”&lt;/a&gt; on twitter. Thousands of ideas were submitted and afterwards Jeff dramatically increased his rate of giving. Through an open competition, the public also helped Bill Gates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businessinsider.com/bill-gates-foundation-helps-invent-tiger-toilets-powered-by-worms-2019-1&quot;&gt;discover a $350 toilet design&lt;/a&gt; for developing countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the public can help foundations identify more opportunities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;launching-billionaireboard-with-covid-19&quot;&gt;Launching BillionaireBoard with COVID-19&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the help of 15 researchers, &lt;a href=&quot;https://billionaireboard.com&quot;&gt;BillionaireBoard&lt;/a&gt; launches today as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The first open dataset on billionaires’ donations &amp;amp; impact investments.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A monthly leaderboard to see who has been contributing the most recently.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An interactive movement where we, the public, can attempt to improve philanthropy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://billionaireboard.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/billionaireboard.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it all starts with a focus on &lt;a href=&quot;https://billionaireboard.com/causes/covid-19&quot;&gt;COVID-19&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the first pieces of the site were coming together, the coronavirus began to spread across the globe. While Governments proved too slow to solve the problem ahead of time, the first reports of Billionaires buying masks for hospitals came out. Then, as federal relief responses were stuck in Congress, some Billionaires began funding ventilator manufacturing and vaccine development. Lastly, as of today, it’s incredible to say that the world’s Billionaires have funded as much COVID-19 scientific research &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcbayarea.com/news/coronavirus/where-is-your-money-going-investigative-unit-tracks-federal-covid-19-spending/2274950/&quot;&gt;as the federal grant system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that Billionaires are “the solution” — just that they are already a major part of it, and clearly want to help. I believe that’s worth embracing and amplifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus far, BillionaireBoard researchers have tracked that 17 billionaires have given or pledged about ~$1.88 billion dollars around the world to mitigate the pandemic, provide PPE to front-line health workers, and work on disease research. We’re still in the early days and expect more giving as the pandemic evolves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://billionaireboard.com&quot;&gt;https://billionaireboard.com&lt;/a&gt; and join today! You can click on each billionaire, learn about their focus areas, and encourage them to provide more funding. Each month the theme of the website will change so we, together, can encourage more types of philanthropy and investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-experiment&quot;&gt;An experiment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll say it now: my background isn’t in philanthropy, and I know achieving results is far more complex than putting a bit of data on a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BillionaireBoard is an experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can we gather all of the data for all 2,200 billionaires?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can we actually accelerate philanthropy through transparency &amp;amp; helping identify new projects?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can we engage with billionaires and their foundations in a useful way?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope so. All we know so far is that Billionaires can make a difference with their wealth. They can help save lives, create innovation, and muster resources. They can convince local Governments to prevent outbreaks and jumpstart scientific advancement. Their immense power comes with great responsibility, and I hope we can all help them use it well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;join-billionaireboard&quot;&gt;Join BillionaireBoard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need help with more important research! Today, BillionaireBoard partially covers ~30 billionaires, so there’s a lot of remaining ground to cover. Anyone can be a researcher by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/billionaireboard&quot;&gt;joining our Facebook Group&lt;/a&gt; and contributing sourced data via “propose edit” buttons on Billionaire’s profiles. All data is verified for accuracy before being posted onto the live website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a software developer, we have an API for submitting data, and if you work for a billionaire or at a foundation, we’d be happy to give you access to ensure the accuracy of your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send me a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zachtratar&quot;&gt;tweet or personal message&lt;/a&gt; to get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//introducing-billionaire-board.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//introducing-billionaire-board.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Balancing Organizations &amp; Oneself</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was at a tech event in San Francisco recently, a CEO was asked how they thought about balancing new initiatives with the core business, and their answer was simple but broadly applicable to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It struck me as particularly the type of advice one can only learn from experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;balancing-an-organization&quot;&gt;Balancing an organization&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All teams across an organization need resources. Most teams don’t have enough people for the goals they set out to achieve, and without these resources, some projects will fail. If your success has stemmed from a unique strategy that continues to win, how can you justify peeling useful resources away from it, and dooming it to a larger probability of failure in the name of new, unvalidated initiatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can imagine there are a bunch of “good” answers: analyzing opportunity-cost, finding new markets with higher growth rates, cultivating higher margin revenue streams, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the reality was more simple than analytical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the organization is doing too many things. When this is true, the product will often stagnate, sales people will report more losing deals, and teams will slow down. You will start to lose too many battles. This is obvious when it is starting to happen, and most in the organization — especially leadership — will have the strong, innate urge to focus resources. People don’t like to lose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, sometimes the organization isn’t doing enough things, and the larger, cash-cow teams will grow and grow until you see folks working on things that clearly aren’t critical — they will become the metaphorical “cog in the machine,” spinning because they’re supposed to, but going nowhere. In this scenario, especially in the technology industry, innovators in the company — especially leadership — will have the strong, innate urge to launch more impactful projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no necessary deeper analysis. Instead, the organization — while it’s growing — is naturally bouncing back and forth between two &lt;em&gt;feelings&lt;/em&gt;. And these feelings tend to be obvious, as long as people are honest with themselves and their teammates. Thus, striking a balance is about being aware of your feelings and the feelings of those around you. [0]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if no one feels strongly either way, then you’re probably sufficiently balanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;balancing-yourself&quot;&gt;Balancing yourself&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve been thinking about this idea for a while, I think this approach is applicable to self-management as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we stumble around our life journeys, we often fail over and over again. Eventually, once we find something we’re kinda good at, we cling to it and it becomes a part of our routine &amp;amp; identity. Although continuous practice is a key to success, people often go overboard: they stick to what they find comfortable and close themselves off from new, potentially risky experiences. Discovering new skills, friendships, and responsibilities requires us to sacrifice our successful routines and identities in the face of likely discomfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how can we think about balancing our existing “successful” routines with new experiences?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A common analytical approach in life coaching is to leverage the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wheeloflife.noomii.com/&quot;&gt;“Wheel of Life”&lt;/a&gt;. With it, you rank your life in several various categories, and then create action plans to try new things in the areas you are weak. This works to an extent, but the method has many gaps [1]. Answering the question “should I try more things?” might be easier with an emotional approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people are trying too many things, they bounce around frantically, lose focus, and rarely make progress on bigger tasks/goals. So ask yourself: How do you feel about your progress as of late, and is that progress meaningful to your desired identity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, when people don’t try enough new things, their chances of finding their innate passions, talents, and interests plummet. So ask yourself: How passionate do you feel, and how much have you discovered about yourself lately?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no necessary deeper analysis; you just have to be aware of your feelings. If you aren’t passionate (with or without progress), expose yourself to new experiences. If you are passionate, but feel as though you’re not making good progress, try fewer things and focus on that which is most important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re both passionate and making progress, congratulations, you’ve probably found your balance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Footnotes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[0] This has cultural implications. It’s a lot easier to balance an honest organization than one where people either ignore problems, or perceive everything as urgent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] The Wheel of Life doesn’t account for identity, talents, or interests. The metrics only exist to force you to judge yourself relativistically.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//balancing-organizations-and-oneself.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//balancing-organizations-and-oneself.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Training Motivation with a Slow Computer</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago, I was reflecting on my life and realized something weird: for the first time in my life, I was unusually… &lt;em&gt;organized&lt;/em&gt;. And not just with my physical world, but with my thoughts, plans &amp;amp; actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-sudden-change&quot;&gt;A Sudden Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This felt strange. I was never a particularly organized person. I never made my bed, left things out on kitchen counters, forgot dishes in the sink &lt;em&gt;(the most evil action of them all)&lt;/em&gt;, and let the mail pile up. Heck, if someone wants to contact me, that’s what email is for, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this chaos was normal for me, and when I thought of who I was, I had kind of accepted this lifestyle. It didn’t seem all that bad. I was doing ok. People care about this stuff too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So fast forward to my moment of reflection, and all of the sudden everything was… mind-blowingly different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I was different.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was no eureka moment, no being “fed up” with the mess, and no spur of insight. I honestly couldn’t explain what had changed or why it had changed, but I was definitely thinking differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of letting messes accumulate, I was defaulting to organization. I simply had the energy to do it, and I would do it. When I had a thought, I’d write it down and internalize it. Wonderfully, I felt like I was starting to truly understand myself as I would write things down, and that feeling created a feedback loop leading to more thoughts, more understanding, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recording my thoughts habitually into Evernote&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Journaling every now and then&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintaining a to-do list, and crushing it&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working in sprints (3 hours on, 30 mins off)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Planning every month, week, and day down to the detail&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And more…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never had a theory of why I changed, or how, until now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;was-i-accidentally-training-my-attention--willpower&quot;&gt;Was I accidentally training my attention &amp;amp; willpower?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After being recommended the book for the 10th time, I gave in and started to read “Thinking Fast and Slow” by Dan Kahneman. In the book, Dan starts by highlighting numerous psychological studies &amp;amp; their often surprising results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these studies were later proven false, but to the best of my research the one I’m about to mention has retained validity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Dan &amp;amp; the team of researchers, attention and self-discipline are linked. Some people are naturally better at controlling their attention, and those people rank higher on many aptitude tests including those measuring intelligence. The most jarring thing though, for me, was that they all also tend to exhibit much higher rates of organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In subsequent tests, people were told to play video games that required them to continuously build upon their attention &amp;amp; self-discipline. Have you ever played Mario, and because you’re going for all-out speed, you make a silly mistake? Yeah, that’s the opposite of self-discipline in this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The people who played the game were able to increase their ability to stay focused throughout, and then those improvements &lt;em&gt;actually transferred over to other tasks&lt;/em&gt;. Those who played the games, and trained their attention, were able to perform better on the same aptitute tests they took prior to playing the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where does this bring me? Was I playing a ton of games, or something? No.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I was — to an extremely stupid degree — training my attention on accident. Like a game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;productivity-starts-with-a-slow-computer&quot;&gt;Productivity starts with a slow computer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my quest to build a startup company with very little money in the bank, I decided I couldn’t afford a shiny, new computer. I had a 2010 Macbook Air, which sounds fine, but the damn thing’s battery was so bad it had to be plugged in at all times. Worse, the CPU would constantly clock down thinking it was going to run out of battery, and everything would move at about ~20% speed every other minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ironically, these were some of the most productive days I ever had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I would sit their coding or designing, the actual movements on the screen, such as my cursor, would lag for seconds. I would sit there and wait, see the result, take another action, and then wait again. It was absurd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I’d show my friends some piece of code, and they’d see the computer running as god-awfully slow as it was, they would freak out at me and be amazed I was getting anything done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But again, these were probably the most productive days of my entire life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sat there waiting — praying — for the computer to do it’s job and compute things for me, I’d never hit alt+tab to check Facebook. I literally couldn’t: alt-tabbing would have made it take 30 seconds longer. While my app was compiling and logs were streaming, I’d just sit there staring at the little black box produce text. I remember it feeling very meditative. I didn’t feel the need to multi-task because I simply couldn’t. When the app had finished compiling, I’d quietly – albeit slowly – get back in the productivity game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, my computer runs fast. When my apps are building, you can bet I’m awkwardly attempting to multi-task &amp;amp; open up a new tab in chrome. My habit of appreciating the slow has faded, and honestly, so has much of the feeling of internal organization. I’m genuinely worse at writing down my thoughts habitually, expounding them in detail, and feeling like I know myself (in general). I clean my apartment regularly-&lt;em&gt;ish&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I’m going to use this potential new insight to try and go slower again, and just see what that does. As stupid as it sounds, this is going to be way more difficult this time around… since my computer is fast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//training-motivation-with-a-slow-computer.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//training-motivation-with-a-slow-computer.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Maxims &amp;amp; Inspiration</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though Spock fans would disagree, we’re all guided by our emotions. When they arise through passion, we can channel them to produce and create wonderous things. When our emotions dull or lower, we have a natural inclination to dwell and despair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I began thinking about this, I grew curious. Could a routine help reinforce productive emotions and truly mitigate – not just ignore – the reverse?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that emotions have two primary sources: preceding emotions and logical deductions. If we believe ourselves to be in a position of greatness, it is easy to get excited and attempt to manifest such a position. If one tells us we are incapable of something or that our ideas have no merit, we question our own capability and reinforce that belief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External happenstances that guide our emotions are unavoidable. Some may consider that to be a bit scary, but we all have a powerful tool to fight the good fight: internal dialogue! With our own thought, we all occasionally have epiphanies – small and large – that makes us &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; good. And we should feel good; we just figured something out! Go team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where do these epiphanies come from and once we have them and how often do they really stick with us? I found that I rarely kept track of mine and, as a result, kept asking myself the same questions over and over again. These epiphanies are logical in nature and wildly differ from person to person, but they certainly affect emotions. Since logic can be re-stated time and time again, perhaps we can use it to our advantage and guide ourselves towards a consistently healthy state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-called-a-maxim&quot;&gt;It’s called a Maxim!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ve probably heard either the terms “Maxim” or “Proverb” before. They mean the same thing: a short statement of truth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Life is really simple, but we insist on making it complicated.” - Confucious&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Very little is is needed to make a happy life; it is all within yourself, in your way of thinking.” - Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You have power over your mind — not outside events. Realize this, and you will find strength.” - Marcus Aurelius&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcus Aurelius, Emperor of Rome, is considered to be one of the wisest men to have ever lived, but even he realized his own weaknesses. So what did he do? He set up a daily routine to battle them. Upon waking, Marcus would recite his own personalized maxims and ponder their meaning; these were quick refreshers that helped guide the rest of his day, week, month, and year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern-society-and-me&quot;&gt;Modern Society and Me&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that modern society prioritizes sources of inspiration in a completely backwards manner: ease-of-discovery dominates efficacy. People hang inspirational posters, collect items on Pinterest, and even go searching for the oh-so-loved “like” on social networks. We look for small glimmers of social proof and meaning through luck — we think “perhaps the outside world holds the same things to be true as my inner self!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much time does that leave for us to focus and reflect upon our own thoughts? Not enough, in my opinion, and oh what a shame! We understand ourselves better than anyone else, which means we &lt;em&gt;resonate with our own, personal discoveries the most!&lt;/em&gt; What would it mean to you if you had an essentially unlimited, effective source of inspiration? We can create sources of daily inspiration that are targeted towards our most foundational of needs, optimized for our current state of life, and — most importantly — &lt;em&gt;guide us specifically towards who we want to be&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although cute, no kitten on a tree that says “hang in there” is going to prove comparable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a little experiment and pushed myself to create a couple maxims every week. As I set aside 15 minutes every morning to go over my own list and think in peace, I found the benefits to be immediete and immense. Just like starting the day with a win by making my bed, I’ve found that I feel more able and positive when I calibrate my thoughts. It makes small problems stay small — or at least &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; small — and become more manageable. Oh, and it makes even the smallest of wins fit into a larger framework, which means their value isn’t simply forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it helped me, I thought I’d share with everyone who might be interested and end up reading this. Here are a couple things I’ve learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It takes repetition. If not every day, every other day seems to be nearly as effective (but there’s definitely a difference).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll eventually have a large list of maxims if you keep at it. As you keep creating, also focus on condensing any overlapping points. It needs to remains clear and concise… which brings me to the next point.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Creating your own maxims helps you understand a little bit more about yourself. Answering “Who am I?” becomes quite a bit easier, and the result more vivid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Targeting your current emotional state when reflecting is really effective. Just lose a battle? Focus on the war.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a proponent of Science, I also want to note that none of this was scientific in the slightest. Shoot me a tweet if you’re thinking about trying this out; I’d love to hear about your discoveries!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//maxims-and-inspiration.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//maxims-and-inspiration.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Followr V1: New Features and Insights</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;http://zachtratar.com/followr.html&quot;&gt;wrote about&lt;/a&gt; and launched Followr two weeks ago, a chrome extension designed to help people gain traction on twitter through automated means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was truly surprised by people’s reactions. I expected to be crushed by the community, but nearly everyone was kind and positive.  Oh – there was one person who called me mentally delusional. &lt;em&gt;Thanks, stranger!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received so much great feedback that I decided to act quickly. Today, I’m releasing Followr v1.0.0, the 2nd public release. You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://ztratar.github.io/followr&quot;&gt;download it here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features-in-v1&quot;&gt;New Features In V1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;History &amp;amp; Conversion Tracking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now see what actions Followr is taking in the “History” page. When favorites convert into followers, the specific tweet is marked as “Converted!” You can also see your total gained followers from Followr on the “Setup” page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Granular Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most requested features was a blacklist, and so it came to be. Followr will never favorite tweets that contain words in the blacklist. Multi-word search queries were also returning poorly relevant results, so Followr now searches for exact query strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Interface &amp;amp; Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous interface was missing a lot of highly relevant information. The new tutorial guides and informs new users. The extension popout now shows you which account Followr is using. I rebuilt the entire interface front the ground up, so pictures will do more justice than words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/followrV1/setup-tab.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/followrV1/history-tab.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/followrV1/progress.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stealth / Anti-Detection Improvements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening up Followr would previously append a ?followr=true variable to the window — lame. Followr now uses script injection to control Twitter’s native frontend controls. The time interval that dictates when Followr runs has also been randomized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-whats-next&quot;&gt;So, what’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is still much work to be done and Followr is open-source, so let me know if you want to help out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Query Effectiveness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m satisfied with the interface and basic favoriting mechanisms, I want to make fewer actions convert into more followers. To do this, the search queries will be optimized using previous data. I would probably be able to do a better job on this if I centralized some data, but I’m not sure that’s a good choice. Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Cleanup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I admittedly fell into callback hell. The code could use a good ol’ refactoring to become squeaky clean. I’m thinking about implementing the next version using Promises, which would be quite fun. The CSS is also getting quite gross — I’ll switch over to LESS &amp;amp; Grunt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-lovely-reviews&quot;&gt;Some lovely reviews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;full&quot; src=&quot;/img/posts/followrV1/reviews.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//followrv1.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//followrv1.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Popcorn Time And Tech's Duty To Do The Right Thing</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;When I first started writing this post, I didn’t know where it would end up. This post covers many topics — maybe too many — so I want to emphasize one thing right now: the last section means the most to me. If you’re only going to read for 15-20 seconds, please skip to the last section. Thanks, Zach.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-apathy&quot;&gt;My Apathy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I vividly remember the first time I used Napster. I was 10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cousin and I were playing video games when his older sister began to play a new Blink-182 song on her computer. I ran over to check it out and saw a blue download bar moving at speeds I had never seen - turns out my Uncle had just bought a T1 internet connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cousin and I stayed up all night downloading music illegally. We didn’t know any better. We had only a faint idea of copyright law and this program, so readily accessible, surely didn’t &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; bad. Bad things are hard to do, &lt;em&gt;right?&lt;/em&gt; Plus, this was fun! Bad things can’t be fun, &lt;em&gt;right?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I stopped downloading and torrenting files years ago, I was never truly disturbed by pirating. I didn’t like the idea of taking someones work for free, but my disdain wasn’t at a level where I felt like I wanted to say anything, let alone take action. When I watched Governments destroy the lives of The Pirate Bay creators, I vilified the Governments. If my friend loaded up a torrent to stream on a projector, I wouldn’t think twice… I’d just go in the kitchen and make some popcorn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;popcorn-time&quot;&gt;Popcorn Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was shown Popcorn Time a couple weeks ago and my mind was subsequently blown. Popcorn Time was beautiful — it was the first beautiful pirating application I had ever seen. I could search for nearly any movie and have it playing in a matter of seconds with two clicks. This was something my Mom could use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time, in that brief moment of realization, I felt scared — even sorry — for the media industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they say, with great power comes great responsibility. Popcorn Time is too good at what it does. I know where to draw the line for my own uses of technology, but most ten year olds, for example, aren’t going to give a shit. Nothing easy and fun can be that bad, &lt;em&gt;right?&lt;/em&gt; They’re going to download and download until one day, their parents finally ask “Hey, what is that?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, you know, “it’s just this app where I can get any movie for free!” Many parents won’t know any better. The kids will install it for them, skip the fear-provoking warning screen, and move the entire, blissfully ignorant family into torrenting territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This territory has been historically small due to the illicit nature of piracy and its accompanying environment. Back in the early 2000s, Napster, Limewire, and Kazaa were distribution machines for not only music, but also computer viruses. If people didn’t weren’t technically savvy, they were likely to download something stupid and brick their computer. Many people chose to not run the risk. The suspect conditions surrounding piracy still live today; most torrenting sites are plastered with porn ads and get-rich-quick schemes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with all of these things preventing piracy, over half of all Americans have admitted to partaking. Half — that’s a lot!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://images.dailytech.com/nimage/Piracy_Percentages_Wide.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remove the unpleasing experience from piracy and what can happen? Popcorn Time will not be the last application open this door. It has proven that you can layer a great, seemingly clean experience on top of an illicit foundation. They’ve shown that doing so can result in a flock of people wanting more — after all, everyone needs to save money in these tough times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how many people would use something like Popcorn Time, but I think the number could be extraordinarily high — so high that it may not only do significant damage, but also shake the media industry into a partial collapse. I don’t want that to happen. The media industry creates beautiful pieces of artwork that help inspire and define generations. It enables dreams and floods people with shared imaginations in a sometimes otherwise dark world. It’s an important asset for this nation and the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-media-industry&quot;&gt;The Media Industry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The media industry knows they need to adapt to continue making money, but how should they adapt? It’s a difficult question to answer, so let’s get some perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire music industry, for example, is not massive — overall revenue last year was only $16.5 billion. WhatsApp, a single company, sold for $19 billion to Facebook last month. The kingpins of media are attempting to protect their revenue streams to the best of their abilities and they see piracy as their primary enemy. With limited capital, the best means of exerting power is through… you guessed it, Government!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for them (and us), they don’t collectively understand technology. Every attempt they make to fix copyright protection results in proposed legislation that tramples internet freedom. I think there are many people in tech who would be on their side if real compromise was put on the table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As ineffective as the media industry may be at proposing such compromise, I’m also seeing apathy from tech industry leadership. We constantly put the ball in the media industry’s court to create legislation before we say “No! That sucks too!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So again, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; should they adapt?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may be controversial, but I don’t think they possess the abilities to cleanly save themselves. If they’re on their own, I believe there will be collateral damage. Internet freedom will continually be in the crosshairs, albeit unnecessary, if the media industry doesn’t get help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think the goals for the media industry are pretty clear, so why doesn’t the tech industry give it a shot?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legislation that hits a good middle ground is possible if and only if the right people are working on it. I think the leaders of the tech industry need to to go the extra mile, work with Hollywood, and spearhead their own version of fresh, internet-preserving copyright protection law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;doing-the-right-thing&quot;&gt;Doing The Right Thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just ranted about the media industry — can these same concepts be generalized? Should they be? Let’s think philosophically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology possesses great power — the likes of which are being scrutinized by the world. Who are these techies on buses? Why can’t I afford rent anymore? Why are robots replacing hard-working people in factories?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As technology moves forward, it is inevitable that it will grow in both good and bad ways. “Software is eating the world” — think about that sentence for the second. To engineers it is a rallying cry for beautiful efficiency, to others it sounds flat out horrifying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re all human. Transition is extremely hard — it is emotionally draining upon individuals and society. For technology to make the most optimal impact, it must be smooth and welcomed, its benefits clear as day and its intentions unquestionably pure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People should be uniting around Science and Technology, not against it. Technology must be viewed as something magical instead of malicious. It is so easy for technology, computing especially, to seem cold, self-interested, and reckless; making it friendly, warm, and benevolent will take effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology has enabled piracy to flip the media industry upside down and that is just the beginning. Very soon, technology will start having more pronounced effects on labor and manufacturing through 3D printing and the internet of things. We won’t be talking about piracy and media then, we’ll be talking about millions of jobs and economic conditions never studied in recorded history. As a whole, our quest for innovation must be balanced with careful wisdom and — I’ll say it — an appreciation for the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot enact change that affects billions of lives and then say “fend for yourself, figure out the new rules”. I believe we must hold out our hands, share   a vision for what is newly possible, and, most importantly, show people what role they can play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is in our ability — &lt;em&gt;no ones else’s&lt;/em&gt;, and thus I believe it is our duty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to my friends for feedback on this post: Andrew Chapello, Andrew Hsu, Peter Pelberg, and Mustafa Khan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//popcorn.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//popcorn.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>Followr, Twitter Bots, and Ethical Considerations</title>
                                <description>&lt;p&gt;Twitter has a massive problem: new users have an extremely difficult time getting started. People who give it a chance and invest real time into the network usually fizzle out after a couple days, leaving without a clue as to what makes it great. Case in point: I now consider myself an active Twitter user, though it took 6 tries and 5 years to finally ‘get it’. Oh, and I’m in the frigin’ tech industry!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you join Twitter you have no followers — it’s like being brought into an empty room and being told “have fun!” Even though you can stare at a wall for 2 minutes before leaving, the average person is going to leave a heck of a lot quicker. You can import your friends and contacts lists, but that’s a long shot – chances are those people aren’t using Twitter either. For people to follow you, you need to fill out a fancy bio, tweet some interesting things, and hope people find you by luck. Oh, but Twitter’s sign up process must help… right? Wrong. It tells you to follow influencers, the people who are least likely to listen to what you have to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these barriers hit you in the face before you derive any value from the product. I believe Twitter has a potential thousands of times greater than its current footprint, but it has to fix this problem. Until it does, I believe helping them out a bit to be a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;opportunity-in-the-depths&quot;&gt;Opportunity In The Depths&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beauty of Twitter is its simple architecture. There is a lot you can do with it; even though the default functionality is lacking, we can make it better ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we make Twitter better? I think there can be many pieces to this puzzle and now is the time to get creative. One of the best solutions I’ve found lies in the most controversial of places: automation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every “traditional” twitter bot I’ve seen was written with two goals in mind: First, to avoid detection and second, to gain followers in vast numbers. Absolutely everything else is at the expense of these two goals, and thus, bots tarnish the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That got me thinking, could you make a bot that truly enhances the network?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I asked around, many people seemed to have a vendetta against all automation within social networks. I think this is due to historically poor bot design. Automation itself is not bad, but is in fact critical to the effectiveness of all modern applications. Certain tasks simply suit themselves towards automation: email newsletters, notification clustering, information collection and analysis, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter bots can take many types of actions, including following and then unfollowing users, auto-replying, and favoriting tweets. All of these actions are disingenuous, favoriting being the least. That’s the negative. The positive lies with the cold, hard fact that favoriting tweets gets you followers — the same possible followers you likely need as a new user to make Twitter useful. So what if you could outweigh the negative with the positive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;introducing-followr&quot;&gt;Introducing Followr&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I’m releasing a little project called &lt;a href=&quot;http://ztratar.github.io/followr&quot;&gt;Followr&lt;/a&gt; to the public. Followr is a Twitter bot, pure and simple, but it aims to be very different than the status quo in three ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instead of being a menace to the Twitter ecosystem, &lt;strong&gt;Followr’s goal is to be the first truly tasteful bot&lt;/strong&gt; — the first bot designed to actually help holistically improve Twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Followr is open-source&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ll be happy if others pitch in to make it even better.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Followr is a chrome extension. It uses the native Twitter website as a proxy to work its magic, so &lt;strong&gt;it can’t be shut down with ease&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference between Followr and traditional Twitter bots lies in the net value created. A tasteful bot does vastly more good than harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be lying if I said Followr is a ‘pure’ tool. The truth is that results matter more: Followr makes Twitter a more friendly, usable network. It enables more people to discover you through shared interests. It can theoretically help give a voice to every individual whose at an unfair advantage because they came to the game late. I sincerely hope it can help you as it has helped the others I started it for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-it-work-how-will-it-work&quot;&gt;How does it work, how will it work?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first version, released today, has minimal functionality. It takes a list of topics you like, searches for tweets about them, and favorites a couple of them. Whereas traditional bots favorite a massive amount of tweets and spam, Followr only favorites 12 or so tweets every 30 minutes your browser is open. For Twitter members with high follower counts this won’t do much, but for those new to the system it can make the experience. Followr also rewards you with more favorites when you interact with others through legitimate discussions and retweets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though much improvement is still possible, after observing the habits of users, I’ve found that Followr, in its current form, creates a net positive value. I think it could made substantially more effective by implementing and improving in some key areas, such as the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intelligent Tweet Selection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some automatically favorited tweets will resonate with you while others won’t. A better bot can increase the number of the former and minimize the latter, making the favorites more valuable and giving you better connections with better people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Behavior Driven Rewards&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning on Followr and never going back to Twitter would be a terrible thing. This is why Followr should learn your behavior over time and reward you for doing good. If you use Twitter like a bot, Followr should ideally shut itself off. There are many ideas that can be explored in this vertical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many people followed me organically vs Followr? Right now, the analytics for that answer aren’t built. Followr can’t do some basic things, like give weighted priority to one topic over another or check if you’re already followed by a user it’s favoriting. It also has a severe “pretty graph” deficiency, which most certainly requires a remedy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whatever you can think up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have an idea? We can talk about it on Github Issues or on Twitter! Shoot me a tweet &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/zachtratar&quot;&gt;@zachtratar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some will disagree with this approach and that’s ok. I know it’s a tad controversial, but I find it naive to deem good automation impossible. It can be done. Since Followr is a chrome extension, it will auto-update on people’s browsers as improvements are created. I’m excited to what the future holds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ztratar.github.io/followr&quot;&gt;You can download Followr here&lt;/a&gt;. If you like it, please review it! Don’t like it? I’m all ears.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//followr.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//followr.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
                        <item>
                                <title>My Reply To Senator Feinstein</title>
                                <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dianne Feinstein, Senator for California and Head of the Intelligence committee, just sent out an email supporting the NSA surveillance programs. I put her email in the comments section and the PDF she attached can be found &lt;a href=&quot;/files/Feinstein-Chronicle.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, if you want to read the full text. This is my reply.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Senator Feinstein,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all due respect, the beginning line in your second paragraph has already been proven untrue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“First, please be assured that the NSA does not conduct mass surveillance on U.S. citizens.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is well known now that the NSA conducts varies degrees of dragnet data collection. If you are limiting the definition of surveillance to only information that is being looked at &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt; by human eyes, then you would be correct. I believe that dragnet data collection is surveillance. My actions, my words, my emotions – everything – is collected. It may not be scrutinized now, but it can be scrutinized later. Any such program removes ones freedom to act – people act different when watched. Usually for the better, I’ll admit, but that is certainly not for the Government to decide. The Sedition acts of the 1800s are a prime example, and I believe this to be of equivalent importance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Americans need liberty. The world needs liberty. It is a constitutional requirement that my liberty be protected, and unfortunately, I see it slipping away week by week as select people claim there is no surveillance. How far will you go to fight for my liberty?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I only ask one thing: please ensure you understand the issue from this perspective – the perspective where definitions are a bit more cloudy than Merriam-Webster. The perspective where pure data collection is a form of surveillance and must be stopped in all forms of dragnet operation. When you vote or propose legislation moving in that direction, you re-affirm a vote from me and thousands of others. When you vote for dragnet data collection, you are voting to limit liberty in all its forms – the antithesis of American pride and power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Precedent is important and I understand the kind of position you’re in is not only complicated, but career-threatening. As the head of the Intelligence community, it may seem that many advocates promoting the same things as me aren’t listening to your side. That might be true, but I sincerely hope that doesn’t lead towards an overall generalization clouding the righteous passions of many citizens. That would be a travesty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want my children to live in a United States of America that promotes peace and, instead of pushing forward the status quo of “us vs them” and “terrorists are inherently evil at birth”, does its best to resolve these issues through intelligent foreign policy and humanitarian aid. I want to live in an America that is a shining city on top of a hill – one that strives to take the high road at every possible moment. Terrorism is a tricky issue – the issue of the century – but it cannot be solved by brute force means. Terrorism is deep-seated anger, hate, and revenge. It is irrational, yet that doesn’t mean it has to be fought with irrational or impure means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founding fathers said that freedom is achievable when liberty is balanced with order. I believe strongly in order, but we also must try different approaches to achieve it and hold each program underneath a spotlight that ranks effectiveness and efficiency. The net loses for Americans through the NSA programs severely outweigh the benefits we derive if, and only if we can maintain order and security through other means.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are these other means? I’d like different answers explored through our great legislative and governmental processes. Please make that happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a good day,
Zach&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                                <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
                                <link>http://zachtratar.com//feinstein.html</link>
                                <guid isPermaLink="true">http://zachtratar.com//feinstein.html</guid>
                        </item>
                
        </channel>
</rss>
